<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Touch Recipe Book</title>
      <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/</link>
      <description>Artists and others offer their favourite recipes to mark the 25th anniversary of Touch</description>
      <language>en</language>
      <copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 19:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/</generator>
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs> 
      
       <item>
         <title>M*A*S*H</title>
         <excerpt>M*A*S*H Cocktail</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>5 parts gin and one moment of silence for the vermouth</p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/recipes/mash-cocktail.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/recipes/mash-cocktail.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>

            <item>
         <title>Peader Kirk</title>
         <excerpt>A cocktail for Brexit</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1 measure cynical politicians<br />
1 measure xenophobia<br />
a dash of Tories claiming they will fund the NHS</p>

<p>Shake vigorously</p>

<p>Thrown down the sink</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/peader_kirk.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/peader_kirk.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 12:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
      
            <item>
         <title>Peter O&apos;Donovan</title>
         <excerpt>&quot;15C&quot; (plum and ginger gin martini)</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Muddle a little fresh ginger and one quarter plum in 3/4 oz dry vermouth<br />
Add 1 1/4 oz of plum infused gin<br />
Stir well on ice<br />
Double strain into a chilled martini glass</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/peter_odonovan.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/peter_odonovan.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 14:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Simon Fisher Turner</title>
         <excerpt>Champagne and Night Nurse</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>When the chemist opens…</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/simon_fisher_turner.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/simon_fisher_turner.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 22:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>BJNilsen</title>
         <excerpt>London Pub Walk</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>In 2012 I received a scholarship from the Leverhulme Trust for a one-year Artist in Residency at the UCL Urban Laboratory in London, to introduce sound as an art practice to urban scholars and students. As part of my research I decided to dérive the city. </p>

<p>Start:</p>

<p>The Euston Tap, Euston</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Bloomsbury Tavern, Bloomsbury</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>Princess Louise, High Holborn</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Angel, St. Giles's</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Red Lion, Soho</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Golden Lion, St. James's</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Windsor Castle, Victoria</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Prince of Wales, Kennington</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Rose and Crown, Clapham</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Prince of Wales, Clapham</p>

<p>»</p>

<p>The Moon Under Water, Balham</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/bjnilsen_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/bjnilsen_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 18:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Carl Michael von Hausswolff</title>
         <excerpt>Jonathan Jonsson</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1. pour 2 dl red Rioja wine in a straight glass</p>

<p>2. pour 2 dl SevenUp and 8 cl Absolut vodka, with some ice,  in a shaker and shake it.</p>

<p>3. pour the shaked and chilled contents in the straight glass and stir.</p>

<p>4. put two red coktail cherries in the glass.</p>

<p>serve</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/carl_michael_von_hausswolff_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/carl_michael_von_hausswolff_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Dave Knapik</title>
         <excerpt>The Alcapion</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>45ml rye<br />
22.5ml Lillet blanc<br />
22.5ml pineapple juice</p>

<p>Shake over ice. </p>

<p>Double the recipe for whole numbers and more inebriation.</p>

<p>NB. Traditionally, dry vermouth is what is used, but I didn't have any and Lillet has far more character.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/dave_knapik_2.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/dave_knapik_2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Lasse Marhaug</title>
         <excerpt>How to make a decent cup of Tie Luo Han</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Tie Luo Han is a Chinese Oolong tea of the Wuyi Rock tea family. The name translates to Iron Warrior Monk, because it is believed that it was created by a powerful warrior monk with golden-bronze skin, hence the cool kung-fu movie-like name. This is one of my favorite teas. I drink it a lot. Although it’s a mid-priced tea (100 grams is usually around $30, although the price has risen in the last years) I like it better than teas which cost twice more. It’s easily available from online tea shops.</p>

<p>Tie Lup Han has a strong full-bodied taste, with a rich and smooth aftertaste. It works well with food, but the aftertaste will be somewhat lost, so for the full experience drink it on its own. It’s one of the teas which I can drink any time of the day.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/tea_lm.jpg" /></p>

<p>Here’s how you prepare it: </p>

<p>Tie Luo Han is a loose leave tea. No tea bags, so you’ll need a bit more utensils than just a big cup.</p>

<p>If you have tea clams which you use for loose leave tea: throw them in the garbage. Tea clams is an abomination. The difference between bag tea and loose leave tea is that the loose leaves are bigger. They need space to swell. With a tea clam you’re putting them in jail and reducing the full effect. Use a pot (clay or glass, either is fine) or a Gaiwan.<br />
Like other Oolong teas it’s best to brew Tie Luo Han at 90°C. If you don’t have a temperature-specific water boiler just let the water boil up and then cool for a few minutes. Never let water boil excessively – it’s the oxygen which provides taste to the tea. Dead water = dead tea.  The amount of tea is difficult to say. It depends on the size of the pot. Usually about 1/3 of the pot covered by tea (in dry condition) is a good rule. The amount of tea affects the brewing time. After a few times you’ll get a feel for it.<br />
The first brew you throw away and don’t drink. This is to ’wash’ the tea of possible toxins. It also decreases the caffeine levels (80% of the caffeine is released during the first 30 seconds of brewing).</p>

<p>The second brew is the first you drink. Let it brew for approx 30 seconds. The tea should get a light brown colour. Not dark like black tea, but darker than green and white tea.   Pour it into a pitcher from which you pour into the drinking cup(s). Use small drinking cups. It may not look as butch as your big red Manchester United-mug, but the tea will taste better. You should slurp. It adds oxygen and thus more taste.</p>

<p>For the third round let it brew for about 60 seconds. And for the forth and fifth add 15-30 seconds each consecutive round. The third brew is often the best. Your mouth is accustomed to the taste so the tea takes on a drier quality.</p>

<p>Tie Lou Han is good for about 5-6 brews.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/lasse_marhaug.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/lasse_marhaug.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Heitor Alvelos</title>
         <excerpt>Take a glass of water...</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Take a glass of water from Lake Titicaca</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/heitor_alvelos.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/heitor_alvelos.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tim Medcalf</title>
         <excerpt>The Coma </excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Trouble sleeping? Waking up too early? Try "The Coma"</p>

<p>2 shots (88ml) of good bourbon. I'd recommend Woodford Reserve.<br />
1.5 measures (30 ml) of Night Nurse Cold Remedy.<br />
Ice</p>

<p>Hellooooo oblivion!</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/tim_medcalf.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/tim_medcalf.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Mike Harding</title>
         <excerpt>A Nice Cup of Tea</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/teasetup.jpg"></p>

<p>In 1946, just a few years before his death, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Orwell">George Orwell</a> wrote a piece for London's Evening Standard newspaper, "A Nice Cup Of Tea". You can read the full text below. He makes tea in a very different way to me, but this article is part of the centuries-long debate about how to make a good cuppa...</p>

<p><a href="http://www.booksatoz.com/witsend/tea/orwell.htm">www.booksatoz.com/witsend/tea/orwell.htm</a><br />
<br><br />
Here is my recipe...</p>

<p>It is absolutely essential that the water used for making a proper cup of tea is boiling. Do not accept anything less than boiling water poured into a mug (or cup).</p>

<p>1 x <a href="http://www.denby.co.uk/white/white-squares-mug/invt/128010611/">Denby white squares mug</a></p>

<p>Tea - the type of tea depends on what time of day it is that you wish to drink your beverage. I have a cup of Yorkshire Tea first thing, English Beakfast Tea with breakfast, Ceylon Tea late morning and Daarjeeling in the afternoon.</p>

<p>Milk - I always put the milk in first. This is a controversial aspect of tea-making. I use semi-skimmed organic and prefer my tea quite milky. The milk, of course, must also be cold.</p>

<p>Water - the water MUST be boiling hot.</p>

<p>Stir to your desired strength (I personally prefer quite weak tea).</p>

<p>Please remember to recycle your teabag. I put it in the compost bucket for the worms...</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/mike_harding_2.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/mike_harding_2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 16:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Ega Bar</title>
         <excerpt>Chris Gonga&apos;s Balham Falls</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/balhamfalls.JPG"></p>

<p>[Pic: Sandra Jasper]</p>

<p>A vodka-based cocktail found in Touch's local, <a href="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps/place?client=safari&rls=en&oe=UTF-8&redir_esc=&um=1&ie=UTF-8&q=191+Balham+High+Road,+London+SW12+9BE&fb=1&gl=uk&hnear=Camberwell&cid=9980232479761541655">Ega</a>.</p>

<p>Chilled Russian Vodka, Mandarin, Napoleon Liqueuer, Lemon and Gomme topped with Ginger Beer. Served in a cool flute.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.alterega.co.uk/">www.alterega.co.uk</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/ega.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/ega.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 12:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Edwin Pouncey</title>
         <excerpt>Mediaeval Ales</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strong Ale</strong></p>

<p>8 lbs. Hugh Baird brand English Pale malt<br />
1 1/3 lbs. Baird) Pale malt, roasted. <br />
For darker ale, roast to amber: 30 mins. at 225 F. followed by 30 mins. at 300 F. For lighter, roast an hour at 225 F.<br />
around 3 lbs. rolled oats<br />
14 to 16 qts. water (main batch) <br />
14 will produce 1 1/2 gallons of ale; 16 will produce 2 gallons<br />
6 to 8 qts. water (second runnings)<br />
1 pkt, Danstar brand Nottingham ale yeast<br />
1 pkt, Danstar brand Windsor ale yeast</p>

<p>Pre-heat the oven to 225 degrees F. Measure out 1 1/3 lbs. of pale malt, and place it in an e.g. 9 x 13 inch baking pan. When the oven is hot, place the malt in the oven and bake for 30 mins. Then increase the heat and bake another 30 mins. Or, for a lighter colored ale, simply bake 60 mins. at 225 F. Remove and set out to cool.</p>

<p>Sanitize an insulated tun and two fermentation vessels (two 3-gal. food-grade plastic buckets with lids).</p>

<p>Boil water for first runnings (14 to 16 qts.). Crush the malt, mixing the amber (baked) malt with the pale malt. Then mix the oats with the crushed malt well.</p>

<p>If your tun has a false bottom or other similar device, pour in enough boiling water to cover it. Then pour in all of the grain. Finally, slowly ladle the remaining water over the grain, pouring from some height.</p>

<p>Cover the mash tun and let sit 30 mins. Open and stir well, then close and let sit another 3 1/2 to 4 hours. This is a hot mash, so it will need this long period of time to mash (convert the starches into sugars).</p>

<p>Put the water for the second running on to boil. Set up the first fermentation vessel under the drain valve or tube of the insulated tun, and slowly run the liquor from the first mash into the first vessel. Close and set aside to cool.</p>

<p>After the first liquor has been drained out, and when the water for the second running has reached a boil, pour it into the damp grain. Allow to sit for 30 mins, then set up the second fermentation vessel and run this liquor into it. Close the second fermenter, and allow both to cool overnight.</p>

<p>In the morning, sanitize a smaller pan or ladle, a Pyrex measuring cup, and a spoon. Also boil about a cup of water and cool it, covered. Rehydrate the packets of yeast into 3/4 cup of the boiled water. Pour this yeast mixture into the two fermenters, 2/3 into the strong main batch, 1/3 into the second runnings. Use the sanitized ladle to aerate each of the batches (by picking up liquor and pouring it back in turbulently).</p>

<p>Close the fermenters (filling the water locks, if any) and allow to ferment.<br />
<br><br />
<strong>Weak Ale</strong></p>

<p>For 2 1/2 gallons of ale:</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>

<p>4 2/3 lbs. Hugh Baird brand English Pale malt<br />
1 1/2 lbs. rolled oats<br />
13 qts water<br />
1 pkt Danstar brand Nottingham ale yeast<br />
1 pkt Danstar brand Windsor ale yeast <br />
1/4 oz. Light Oak chips </p>

<p>Boil water. Crush the malt, then mix it well, while still dry, with the oats.</p>

<p>Open up the insulated tun and place it on the floor near the stove (where the boiling water is). Pour 2 quarts of water into the tun from a reasonable height, moderately slowly.</p>

<p>Pour all the dry grain into the lauter tun.</p>

<p>Slowly pour 3 more quarts of boiling water over the grain. Don't stir. Put the cover on the tun and let it stand for 10 mins. Then add 1 more quart of boiling water. At this point, there should be a very small amount of visible liquid. Put the lid back on and wait 20 more mins.</p>

<p>Now take the lid off and stir it all up. It should be about the consistency of fairly thick porridge. Put the lid back on and do something else for a while -  at least an hour and a half. (I went out for a beer with some friends for 3 1/2 hours.)</p>

<p>Open up the tun and stir in 3 more quarts of boiling water, and stir. Close up again and wait 25 more mins.</p>

<p>Finally, add remaining boiling water (4 quarts)</p>

<p>Stir well.</p>

<p>Set up the sanitized fermenter. Open the mash tun valve (or otherwise start straining out the wort, that is the liquid part, from the grain. (Unlike modern methods, I did not recirculate the liquid in any way.) The first gallon should go quickly; straining the last gallon should be done somewhat more slowly in order to get most of the liquid out.</p>

<p>Close the fermenter and let the wort cool overnight.</p>

<p>Rehydrate both packages of yeast according to the package instructions (being careful to use water that has been boiled and cooled, and a glass that has been sanitized in some way). Pitch the yeast into the wort, and shake, stir, and otherwise agitate the wort in order to aerate it.</p>

<p>Let the ale ferment for a day; the yeast should have started, and activity should be well under way. Boil the oak chips in approx. 1 cup water. When the water is the color of a cup of tea, take off heat and allow to cool some. Pour off water, then add approx. 1/2 cup of water back into chips. Raise this to a boil again, then allow to cool; it should be just barely darker in color than normal water. Add this oak-water to the wort.</p>

<p>Let the ale ferment for a couple more days. Draw off and serve.<br />
</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/edwin_pouncey.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/edwin_pouncey.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 15:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Randy Gibson</title>
         <excerpt>Peach Tea Julep</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>2 oz. (60 ml) Tea Infused Bourbon<br />
3/4 oz. (25 ml) Simple Syrup<br />
10 mint leaves<br />
3 dashes Fee's Peach bitters (or two slices of fresh peach)<br />
Lemon Slice<br />
Mint Sprig</p>

<p>To make the Tea-infused Bourbon add one strong black tea bag to every 8 oz (240 ml) of Bourbon (I prefer Buffalo Trace or Makers Mark for this). Allow to infuse for 4 hours, remove the tea bags and use. This will keep indefinitely.</p>

<p>To make the simple syrup mix 2:1 parts sugar to water and bring to a light boil. Turn off the heat and allow to cool - kept in the refrigerator this will keep for about a month.</p>

<p>To assemble the julep:</p>

<p>Muddle the mint leaves with the simple syrup and the bitters in a heavy glass. (if using fresh peach, muddle that here as well)<br />
Top with half the Tea-Infused bourbon, stir well and add crushed ice to nearly fill the glass. Add the rest of the bourbon and give a stir. Top the glass off with more crushed ice. </p>

<p>Garnish with a lemon slice and a sprig of mint.</p>

<p>Enjoy on a warm porch with a good breeze and the sun shining.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/randy_gibson.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/randy_gibson.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 08:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Dave Knapik</title>
         <excerpt>Eurovision Song Contest 2009</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Eurovision</p>

<p>This cocktail needs to be sweet and trashy, with a thin veneer of pseudo-sophistication, as well as slightly embarrassing to admit to liking. Eastern Europe should dominate this drink as much as it dominates the contest, though the west should make an appearance as well, just to give the proceedings a surface appearance of fairness.</p>

<p>* 2 parts vodka<br />
* 1 part Pálinka (Hungarian flavoured brandy) ... maybe some other potent Eastern European spirit as a substitute (credit to Kai Hoffman)<br />
* a dash of Angostura Bitters "to represent the dashed hopes of anyone not from east of the Danube" (credit to Jo Tacon)</p>

<p>Eastern Dominance</p>

<p>2 parts vodka<br />
1 part slivovica (Slovakian plum brandy)</p>

<p>Shake with ice and serve in a martini glass</p>

<p>Western Ruin</p>

<p>1 part dry London gin, preferably Bombay Sapphire or Gordon's<br />
1 part French brandy</p>

<p>Shake with ice and serve in a martini glass</p>

<p>The Terry Wogan</p>

<p>This drink must taste bitter and bitchy but be ultimately endearing.</p>

<p>1 part dry London gin, preferably Bombay Sapphire or Gordon's<br />
1 part Jameson Irish Whiskey<br />
a dash of Angostura Bitters</p>

<p>Essentially it's a Smoky Martini with Irish whiskey instead of Scotch and a dash of bitters thrown in.</p>

<p>Wake Up With Wogan</p>

<p>Because some days you require alcohol earlier than others, this is same as The Terry Wogan, but mixed with orange juice to taste to lend it a pre-evening air of respectability. Although generally this should be made with anywhere from four to six parts orange juice, it can be made with as much or as little as you'd like. You can even make it with no orange juice. Yes, I know that would leave you with simply a Terry Wogan, but here's the best bit: you can still call it a Wake Up With Wogan. You're not an alcoholic, you just prefer your Wake Up With Wogan dry.</p>

<p>Douze Points</p>

<p>1 generous glass of your favourite 12 year old Scotch whisky<br />
1 Gauloises cigarette</p>

<p>Smoke this classic French cigarette whilst drinking a fine glass of whisky. If you must speak whilst enjoying your twelve points, you are required to do so in English with a fake, vaguely Continental accent.</p>

<p>Irelande Douze Pointe</p>

<p>1 pint of Guinness<br />
1 shot of Ouzo 12</p>

<p>Sink the shot in the Guinness and it's 2008 with turkeys all over again!</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/dave_knapik_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/dave_knapik_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 16:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Philip Jeck</title>
         <excerpt>Elderflower Champagne</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients:</p>

<p>4/5 large heads of elderflowers, picked on a dry sunny day, fully open. This is usually in the early June in the UK.<br />
1kg sugar<br />
2 lemons<br />
4 tablespoons of white wine vinegar<br />
10 litres of cold water</p>

<p>Equipment:</p>

<p>10 litre vessel (like a plastic bucket)<br />
Bottles that are strong enough to take the pressure of the gas produced (like litre tonic, lemonade bottles)<br />
a large jug<br />
a small jug<br />
a lemon squeezer<br />
a funnel<br />
a potato peeler or sharp small knife<br />
a tablespoon<br />
a sieve<br />
a strainer or fine clean muslin</p>

<p>Method:</p>

<p>Make sure all the equipment used is sterilised and well rinsed (very important or it will go bad).<br />
Wash the lemons and peel finely as possible the rind. <br />
Remove any insects, leaves or any other objects from the flowerheads, don't wash them.<br />
Squeeze the lemons and put the juice in the 10 litre vessel with the rind and flowers.<br />
Add the sugar and wine vinegar, carefully so as to not crush the flowers<br />
Pour on the water and stir gently. Cover and leave to stand 24 hours,<br />
Stir gently about every 6 hours.<br />
After 24 hours take off cover and remove any large pieces of flower heads and rind<br />
Use small jug to pour some liquid into large jug through the sieve. When large jug is full, place the funnel into a sterilised bottle and pour liquid through strainer/muslin into bottle. Repeat for all of the bottles, screw caps on firmly and leave somewhere not hot or cold.<br />
	<br />
After 2/3 weeks it will be ok to drink but the longer left the more the flavour develops.</p>

<p>It will last up to a year. When opening be careful it can be very lively!</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/philip_jeck.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/philip_jeck.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 15:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Philip Marshall</title>
         <excerpt>Bloody Mary</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Simple is best.</p>

<p>2 parts vodka<br />
3 parts tomato juice<br />
A liberal splash of Worcestershire Sauce<br />
5 jolts of Tabasco</p>

<p>In addition, freshly ground black pepper and a sliver of lemon are musts, as are celery salt and a stick of celery with which to stir - it needs to be stirred, and a spoon or a straw simply will not do, or so I am advised. Anyone who bolts on further complexities to this God of drinks must be shot.</p>

<p>To be drunk over ice, whilst wearing vintage Comme des Garçons and toasting dear friends in Antwerp and Berlin.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/philip_marshall.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/philip_marshall.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Beverages</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
      
   </channel>
</rss>