<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Touch Recipe Book</title>
      <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/</link>
      <description>Artists and others offer their favourite recipes to mark the 25th anniversary of Touch</description>
      <language>en</language>
      <copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 19:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/</generator>
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Rochelle Bates</title>
         <excerpt>90 Second Cup Cake (SCD legal, Paleo, Gluten and grain-free, sugar free)</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>I can’t eat any grains or starches that you’d find in traditional or even Paleo baked goods, so I eat this most mornings, it’s like a muffin. Good with coffee or tea in the morning :) and . Cup Cake pour la Gâteau dans une tasse</br>

<p>You need a microwavable bowl to cook this; I use a medium-sized euro-style coffee bowl/cocoa cup, it is about 3.5 inches tall and 6 inches across with sides that slope up. If you use a real cup or mug it needs to be quite oversized – the cake will rise up over the top and then fall a bit; fruit may fall out if you use a mug, so place a plate under the cup while cooking in a mug or smaller bowl.</p>

<p>1/3 cup Super-fine almond flour (make sure it is super-fine or it will have the texture of coarse cornmeal)</br>
1 jumbo egg or 2 medium eggs</br>
1-2 Tablespoons honey (Omit if you are sugar-free)</br>
1/4 tsp cinnamon (I put in 2 big shakes of Trader Joe’s)</br>
1/2 tsp vanilla (capful of Trader Joe’s)</br>
1/8 tsp baking soda</br>
1-2 tsp of unsweetened coconut</p>

<p>Optional: ½ mashed very ripe banana</p>

<p>Butter for topping</p>

<p>2/3 cup or so fresh berries — you can use thawed, frozen fruit, but drain very well or it will make the cake mushy, too much liquid. I usually use blueberries or raspberries or mix of the 2, Blackberries need to be added at the end of cooking, as they are so juicy.

I’ve also used: peaches, fresh or thawed, dehydrated berries (they end up the consistency of raisins), about ½ cup grated/minced apple or ¼ cup applesauce (mix into the batter).

Whisk all of the ingredients until smooth. If you are using banana, mix it in now with all of the other ingredients. Make sure to scrape the batter down off of the walls of the bowl/cup. 

Scatter the berries or chopped peaches on top of the batter, using enough to cover most of the surface, but don’t mound up or anything like that. The berries fall through the cake so you don’t have to push the fruit down. 

Cook on high for 2 minutes 20 seconds; the surface crust on top might be moist from the fruit, but should be cooked through. If there is unbaked batter visible, nuke the cake for another 25-30 minutes (and don’t use as much fruit next time &#x263a; ). 

If you are using blackberries, cook for 90 seconds, then top with blackberries so that the entire top surface is covered, and cook an additional minute. You can add the blackberries to the cupcake that already has fruit in it, or top the plain cupcake.

Top cup cake with thin slices of butter, loosen the cake from the sides of the cup and slip butter slices down there, and make slits in the top of the cake and put butter in those. Think of it as a butter sponge :). Use as much or as little butter as you like.

Cut the cup cake into bite-sized pieces, or unmold the cake from the cup and eat like a muffin. Best when HOT!

If you are a Paleo person or just gluten-free person you can eat maple syrup! You can omit or reduce the honey and top with butter and maple syrup for a uper-fast blueberry pancake tasting treat!

<p>Version 2: follow recipe as above, but omit added fruit – you can still add the mashed banana or applesauce to the batter. Cook for only 90 seconds when there is no fruit, just a cup cake to bake.

You may need to add 20 seconds or so if you’ve used banana or applesauce. Top with homemade 10 minute fruit compote (see recipes!)

Savory version: add grated cheese and chili flakes, or maybe cheese and bacon to the batter — savory instead of sweet, so omit vanilla, cinnamon, coconut or honey.</p>

<p>*This is based on a recipe in a wonderful grain-free cookbook: BAKING FOR THE SPECIFIC CARBOHYDRATE DIET by Kathryn Anible.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipes/rochelle-bates-cup-cake.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipes/rochelle-bates-cup-cake.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 01:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item> 

            <item>
         <title>Bethan Kellough</title>
         <excerpt>Scones</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>40ml sunflower oil<br />
300g flour<br />
teaspoon of baking powder<br />
60g caster sugar<br />
100g dried fruit eg raisins<br />
150ml soya milk</p>

<p>Pre-heat the oven to 375ºF.</p>

<p>Mix together the baking powder, oil and flour. Add sugar and raisins. Add the soya milk and fold in little by little. The dough shouldn't quite stick to your hands... so add more milk or flour as necessary.</p>

<p>Shape into round balls of dough - there should be enough for 6. Bake for about 25 minutes on a tray with a bit of flour to stop them sticking.</p>

<p>Check after 20 minutes... they are ready when the top is a light brown and if you turn them over and tap the bottom, they should make a firm sound rather than a squishy one.</p>

<p>DEVOUR!</p>

<p>I like butter or cream and jam, with <a href="http://touch33.net/recipebook/beverages/mike_harding_2.html">a cuppa</a>!</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/bethan_kellough.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/bethan_kellough.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 20:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>John Chantler</title>
         <excerpt>Homemade Crumpets</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>You need a <a href="http://www.azeliaskitchen.net/how-to-make-easy-sourdough-starter-dan-lepard/">sourdough starter</a>. Best to get some from someone. My partner Carina made ours about two years ago according to Dan Lepard's recipe in his great book 'The Handmade Loaf'. We keep it in the fridge. You can make crumpets with the starter straight from the fridge, but they do like it if you can let the starter warm up a little bit. The texture and crumpet-ness of the finished thing is entirely dependent on how loose/floury your starter is - hard to explain so best just to experiment.</p>

<p>Put 250/300g of starter in a bowl - or whatever amount you would usually remove to make a bread or refresh it. This should make one giant crumpet. This is the best way rather than pretending you only want a small one and using the ring, but up to you. You can always cut it up to share.</p>

<p>Add half a teaspoon of bicarbonate soda to the starter and stir through. Leave starter to sit and swell for a few minutes while you heat a large frying pan and melt a good click of salted butter in the pan so that the bottom and sides are completely covered. Pour in the starter - it will probably gather together in a big clump in the middle, but its best to stretch it out to the sides, reduce the heat a bit. Starter will start to form bubbles…  try to get it so that its almost completely cooked before flipping it to finish off the top.  Bottom should be crispy and a bit salty from the butter. Flip it onto a plate. Honey, cinnamon, greek yoghurt, fruit…  done.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/john_chantler.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/john_chantler.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Feidhlim O&apos;Neill</title>
         <excerpt>My mother&apos;s BROWN BREAD RECIPE, hence the emphasis on imperial measurements....</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/bread.jpg"></p>

<p>Very healthy and easy to make bread. No proofing needed since the rising is a chemical process not organic one. You can add nuts or seeds as desired.</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>

<p>20ozs. Strong brown flour (or 10ozs Canadian Strong Brown and 10ozs normal strong brown)</p>

<p>5ozs. white flour</p>

<p>2ozs. porridge oats</p>

<p>2ozs. wheat germ</p>

<p>1 teaspn (rounded) Baking soda.</p>

<p>625mls =1 ¼ pts Buttermilk or diluted 500ml tub of Yogurt works too</p>

<p>1/4 teaspoon Salt</p>

<p>METHOD</p>

<p>Preheat Over to 180°C</p>

<p>Mix flours, wheat germ and porridge oats in a bowl sieve in soda (to make sure no lumps) and salt.</p>

<p>Mix well then add the buttermilk.</p>

<p>Mix but just enough (a minute or two tops) – if you mix too much the bread will be flatbread – purists say you need to use a wooden spoon for this part.</p>

<p>Mixture should be wet but hold together in a ball.</p>

<p>Use non slick bread tins (for a loaf effect) or more traditionally flattened the mixture on a non stick baking tray.</p>

<p>Sprinkle with more oats if desired.</p>

<p>Bake at 180°C for 30 minutes. Reduce heat to 160°C and bake for a further 20 minutes approx. Its done if you put a skewer into the bread and it comes out dry.</p>

<p>Remove from tin and place on a wire rack to cool.</p>

<p>Enjoy</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/feidhlim_oneill.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/feidhlim_oneill.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 10:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Michael Esposito</title>
         <excerpt>Bread of the Dead</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Pan de Muertos (Mexican Bread of the Dead) </p>

<p>Original Recipe Yield 1 large round loaf <br />
 <br />
Ingredients</p>

<p>	•	1/4 cup margarine<br />
	•	1/4 cup milk<br />
	•	1/4 cup warm water (110 degrees F/45 degrees C)<br />
	•	3 cups all-purpose flour<br />
	•	1 1/4 teaspoons active dry yeast<br />
	•	1/2 teaspoon salt<br />
	•	2 teaspoons aniseed<br />
	•	1/4 cup white sugar<br />
	•	2 eggs, beaten<br />
	•	2 teaspoons orange zest<br />
	•	1/4 cup white sugar (for the glaze)<br />
	•	1/4 cup orange juice (for the glaze)<br />
	•	1 tablespoon orange zest (for the glaze)<br />
	•	2 tablespoons white sugar (for the glaze)</p>

<p>Directions</p>

<p>	•	Heat the milk and the butter together in a medium saucepan, until the butter melts. Remove from the heat and add them warm water. The mixture should be around 110 degrees F (43 degrees C). <br />
	•	In a large bowl combine 1 cup of the flour, yeast, salt, anise seed and 1/4 cup of the sugar. Beat in the warm milk mixture then add the eggs and orange zest and beat until well combined. Stir in 1/2 cup of flour and continue adding more flour until the dough is soft. <br />
	•	Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured surface and knead until smooth and elastic. <br />
	•	Place the dough into a lightly greased bowl cover with plastic wrap and let rise in a warm place until doubled in size. This will take about 1 to 2 hours. Punch the dough down and shape it into a large round loaf with a round knob on top. Place dough onto a baking sheet, loosely cover with plastic wrap and let rise in a warm place for about 1 hour or until just about doubled in size. <br />
	•	Bake in a preheated 350 degrees F (175 degrees C) oven for about 35 to 45 minutes. Remove from oven let cool slightly then brush with glaze. <br />
	•	To make glaze: In a small saucepan combine the 1/4 cup sugar, orange juice and orange zest. Bring to a boil over medium heat and boil for 2 minutes. Brush over top of bread while still warm. Sprinkle glazed bread with white sugar. </p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/michael_esposito_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/michael_esposito_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 15:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Nicki Myers</title>
         <excerpt>3 flour bread</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>for breadmakers...</p>

<p>200 g spelt flour<br />
100 g wholemeal flour<br />
75 g white flour - all flours to be bread flours<br />
280 g warm water<br />
20 g butter<br />
1 1/2 teaspoons salt<br />
1 1/2 teaspoons sugar<br />
1 teaspoon yeast</p>

<p>That's it !</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/nicki_myers.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/nicki_myers.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 17:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Rosy Parlane</title>
         <excerpt>Non-Kneaded Bread</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1 loaf</p>

<p>1 + 1/2 tsp dry yeast<br />
150 mls warm water<br />
1 tblsp honey </p>

<p>Combine and set aside in warm place</p>

<p>1 cup spelt (or wheat) flour<br />
2 cups wholemeal spelt flour<br />
1/4 cup wheat germ or buckwheat flour<br />
1/3 cup bran<br />
1/4 cup kibbled spelt (or whole oats or whole wheat)<br />
2 tsp salt<br />
1/2 cup ground flax seeds<br />
1/2 cup sunflower (or pumpkin) seeds</p>

<p>Combine dry ingredients</p>

<p>Add to water mixture 300mls warm water and 1 tblspn cider vinegar. Pour into dry ingredients and mix until just combined.</p>

<p>Put into greased and floured loaf tin. </p>

<p>Sprinkle with sesame seeds, and leave to rise for one hour</p>

<p>Bake at 180 degrees for 45-50 mins until hollow-sounding when tapped on the top.</p>

<p>Slice and eat with lots of butter.<br />
</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/rosy_parlane.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/rosy_parlane.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Hildur Ingveldardottir Gudnadottir</title>
         <excerpt>Drone Bread (Sourdough Rye Bread)</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>This is a very simple but time consuming recipe. you do not have to "keep the starter alive" in your fridge, like with many other sourdough recipes.</p>

<p>1/2 l rye flour<br />
1/2 l water</p>

<p>step 1.<br />
mix the flour and water and let the "porridge" stand in a bowl with a plate on top in room temperature for 36 hours. after that time there should be a sour smell sneaking out from the bowl (don´t worry it´s not that bad!). this "porridge" is the "starter" of the bread and will lift the bread.</p>

<p>1 1/2 l rye flour<br />
1/2 l water<br />
a little bit of salt</p>

<p>step 2.<br />
mix the rest of the rye, salt and water to the porridge and knead it with everything you´ve got (the dough is pretty massive). the dough also has a tendency to be a bit wet so it´s good to have extra rye on the side to spill over the dough.</p>

<p>step 3.<br />
split the dough into 2 parts and place in 2 buttersmeared bread pans.<br />
let the bread rise for 5 - 6 hours.</p>

<p>step 4.<br />
heat the oven at 175°C</p>

<p>step 5.<br />
bake the bread for 2 hours, but take the bread out of the pans for the last 15 mins so it will be well baked on the sides aswell.</p>

<p>step 6.<br />
let the bread stand for a while before you attack it with a knife (preferrably 24 hours - but i can never wait that long myself....) the bread will be a bit wet in middle for the first day or so, but don´t panic - that is very normal. unlike many a bread this one gets better as it´s gets older. i recommend toasting it and putting some dijon mustard and cheese ontop.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/hildur_ingveldardottir_gudnadottir.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/hildur_ingveldardottir_gudnadottir.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Mike Harding</title>
         <excerpt>Roman Army Spelt Tin Bread</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients:</p>

<p>500g spelt flour<br />
1 tsp sea salt<br />
3 tsp olive oil<br />
1 tsp honey<br />
15g fresh yeast (if available)<br />
400ml warm water</p>

<p>Method:</p>

<p>1. Place the flour in a large mixing bowl.<br />
2. Blend the yeast into half the water and roughly mix into the flour.<br />
3. Dissolve the salt in the remaining water and add to the flour, followed by the oil. Knead for 15 minutes.<br />
4. Leave the dough dusted with flour and allow to rise in a warm place (best covered with a towel to avoid draft) for 20 to 25 minutes.<br />
5. Divide the dough into two large greased bread tins.<br />
6. Preheat the oven to 180C, 370F, Fas Mark 5 and bake for 40-45 minutes.</p>

<p>Tips:</p>

<p>Spray the dough several times with water to make a nice crust.<br />
Take the dough out of the tin and leave to cool down, otherwise bread might go soggy.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/mike_harding.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/breads/mike_harding.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Breads</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
      
   </channel>
</rss>