<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Touch</title>
      <link>https://touch33.net</link>
      <description>Since its first release in 1982, Touch has created sonic and visual productions that combine innovation with a level of 
      care and attention that has made it the most enduring of any independent company of its time.</description>
      <language>en</language>
      <copyright>Copyright 2020</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 07:15:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/</generator>
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
      
            <item>
         <title>Touch: Isolation</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://touch33.net/images/585x/V33.40.jpg" /></p>

<p>28 new and exclusive tracks recorded by Touch artists, with the final track delivered on 25th May 2020. A photographic counterpoint, the view from Hampstead Heath during the London lockdown. <a href="https://touchisolation.bandcamp.com">Touch: Isolation is a subscription project that evolved over April and May 2020. Click here to subscribe.</a></p>

<p>A time to support independent music while it still exists!<p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-isolation.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-isolation.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 11th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                              <item>
         <title>Tone 76 | Budhaditya Chattopadhyay “The Well-tempered City Book l”</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Released 3rd July 2020</p>

<p>1 track - DL only - 19:01</p>

<p><a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com/album/the-well-tempered-city">Now available on Bandcamp</a></p>

<p><img src="https://touch33.net/images/585x/TONE76.jpg" /></p>

<p>The sound work has been conceived using transduction as the methodology to represent citizen-generated vibration contents at the architectural surfaces of contemporary cities. These surfaces serve as physical interfaces for citizens’ sonic interaction with their personified everyday urban structure and objects, such as walking, resting, touching, tapping or hitting on the structural surfaces of the city, including the streets or walls.The vibrations that are generated through such physical interactions, citizens’ participation and intervention are transduced into sounds audible to the human perception using customised accelerometers. These subtle recordings are later treated as sense data of the sonic experience in a computed and composed form. The project facilitate in-depth listening to the architectural and built spaces of today’s cities as living organisms or manmade urban nature, currently resonating with a sense of post-apocalyptic doom due to pandemics, climate catastrophe, global warming, mass migration, and racial differences. How do city-dwellers emotively intervene in and engage with the city in
these contexts? In this work, the city acts as an instrument that produces its own hyper-real and digitally enhanced sounds where surfaces of the evolving buildings are used as strings tempered by human intervention in terms of embodied interaction, thereby citizens becoming part of the work in the mimetic process. The work holds the reflections of the citizen’s immediate emotional situations and affective context in today’s cities.</p>

<p>All sounds recorded, composed and mixed by Budhaditya Chattopadhyay. Recorded on Sound Devices 702 using customized accelerometers.</p>

<p><a href="http://budhaditya.org/">Budhaditya Chattopadhyay</a> is a Media Artist and Scholar based in Denmark</p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/tone-76-budhadit…ered-city-book-l.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/tone-76-budhadit…ered-city-book-l.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on July 7th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Need More Nature? Listen to 12 Essential Field Recordings</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>New York Times, June 3rd 2020</p>

<p>Albums featuring chattering animals and roaring weather systems have blurred the boundaries of music and chance, new age and noise.</p>

<p>by Christopher R. Weingarten</p>

<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/03/arts/music/field-recordings.html">www.nytimes.com/2020/06/03/arts/music/field-recordings.html</a></p>

<p>featuring:</p>

<p><a href="https://chriswatsonreleases.bandcamp.com/album/outside-the-circle-of-fire">Chris Watson - Outside the Circle of Fire</a> | <a href="https://janawinderen.bandcamp.com/album/energy-field">Jana Winderen - Energy Field</a> | <a href="https://chriswatsonreleases.bandcamp.com/album/el-tren-fantasma">Chris Watson - El Tren Fantasma</a> | <a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com/album/eldfjall">Jacob Kirkegaard - Eldfjall</a><p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/need-more-nature…field-recordings.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/need-more-nature…field-recordings.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on June 6th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                             <item>
         <title>Tone 70 | Simon Scott "Migrations"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Released 26th June 2020<p>

<p>Vinyl - 2 tracks + DL - 2 tracks</p>

<p><img src="https://touch33.net/images/585x/TONE70.jpg" /></p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>Side A<br>
1. Red Square</p>

<p>Side AA<br>
1. Murmurations</p>

<p>Bonus tracks (digital only):</p>

<p>3. The Borderlands<br>
4. Fen(ce)</p>

<p>Vinyl in an edition of 300 copies plus digital – with two digital bonus tracks when purchasing from our Bandcamp. Vinyl mastered at SPS Mastering. Cut by Jason @ Transition. Digital mastered by Rafael Anton Irisarri at Black Knoll Studio (NY). Photography and design by Jon Wozencroft.</p>

<p><a href="https://simonscott.bandcamp.com/album/migrations">You can pre-order now on Bandcamp.</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/tone-70-simon-scott-migrations-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/tone-70-simon-scott-migrations-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on June 5th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Strafe F.R. - Friss</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://touch33.net/images/585x/FRISS.jpg" /></p>

<p>Strafe F.R. present a new recording and video, 'Friss', completed after their most recent release "Shadow Position" (Touch Tone 68)</p>

<p><a href="https://youtu.be/mLSxoRwPbwI">youtu.be/mLSxoRwPbwI</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/strafe-f-r-friss.html </link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/strafe-f-r-friss.html </guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May 30th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>TO:6D | Strafe Für Rebellion "Santa Maria"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>"Santa Maria" by Strafe Für Rebellion was one of the very early artist-only releases on Touch, dating back to 1986. It has never been available on CD. This bandcamp release has been sourced from the original quarter-inch master tapes, transferred by Bernd Kastner and S.M. Syniuga. The original artwork marks the first time we were able to afford photo-typesetting for the whole project.</p>

<p>DL - 2 tracks - 44:29</p>

<p>Release date: 3rd April 2020</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1: Santa Maria A<br>
2: Santa Maria B</p>

<p><a href="https://strafefr.bandcamp.com/album/santa-maria">Available from Bandcamp</a></p>

<p><p><img src="https://touch33.net/images/585x/TO6.jpg" /></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/to6d-strafe-fur-…on-santa-maria-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/to6d-strafe-fur-…on-santa-maria-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on April 3rd, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                              <item>
         <title>Touch is 38 Today</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Today, 11th March, is the official 38th anniversary of the founding of Touch in 1982...</p>

<p><span class="smallpic"><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/245x/soulkitchen.jpg" /></span></p>

<p>First contact with New Order after their concert at the Newcastle Mayfair on 11th March 1982…</p>

<p><a href="https://www.touch33.net/full-catalogue-by-date">You can follow our progress year by year here...</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-is-38-today.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-is-38-today.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March 11th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                        <item>
         <title>Hildur Guðnadóttir Wins Academy Award [OSCAR] for Best Original Score</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://touch33.net/artists/hildur-gudnadottir">Hildur Guðnadóttir</a> has won the Academy Award for Best Original Score for 'Joker' [2019]. She also won an EMMY and a GRAMMY (for Chernobyl [HBO, 2019]) and a BAFTA and a Golden Globe for Joker, this claiming a unique clean sweep or 'BEGGO'.</p>

<p>We are so proud to have been part of this journey with such a talented and generous artist. Many congratulations!</p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/hildur-gudnadott…t-original-score.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/hildur-gudnadott…t-original-score.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 10th, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                              <item>
         <title>Another Word for Dive Is Sound by Mandy-Suzanne Wong</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1. The Hydrophonist</p>

<p>Looks barely human. Heavy boots fitted with claws. Limbs and trunk squared off by layers of thermal waterproofing. Something like a spacesuit with miles of cable hanging off it. She’s got no face. She’s all nylon. Orange helmet. Windproof goggles... [Permafrost Magazine]</p>

<p><a href="https://permafrostmag.uaf.edu/permafrost-41-2/another-word-for-dive-is-sound/">Continue reading...</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.janawinderen.com">www.janawinderen.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/another-word-for…ndy-suzanne-wong.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/another-word-for…ndy-suzanne-wong.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on January 1st, 2020</pubDate>
      </item>
      
              <item>
         <title>Tone 71 | Bana Haffar "Genera"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Download album - 1 track - 32:45 minutes</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Genera</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE71.jpg" /></p>

<p>Recorded by Mike Harding, 3rd May 2019 at AB Salon, Brussels<br>
Mastered by Simon Scott @ SPS Mastering<br>
Artwork & photography by Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p>Instruments used:<br>
Eurorack modular: Make Noise René 2, Make Noise Tempi, Make Noise WoggleBug, Make Noise Morphagene, Make Noise QMMG, Make Noise tELHARMONIC, Make Noise Maths, Serge Resonant EQ, Mutable Instruments Shades, Mutable Instrument Clouds
Non-modular: Field recordings made using a Zoom H6 and LOM mikroUsi microphones, GE 35383 Micro Cassette Recorder</p>

<p><a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to order from the TouchShop now</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/tone-71-bana-haffar-genera-live-at-ab-salon-brussels-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/tone-71-bana-haffar-genera-live-at-ab-salon-brussels-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 1st, 2019</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
      <title>Touch presents... Live at Iklectik | 22nd June 2019</title>
      
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/TheMirror.jpg" /></p>
      
      <p>A rare UK performance from Daniel Menche and a a new audiovisual immersive cinema performance "The Mirror" by People Like Us;</p>
      
      <p><em>The Mirror is a live a/v performance which splices together movie snippets with unique sample-based music exploring the masks 
      that we wear represented through the lens, using parallel narratives across the screen to depict an ever-changing stream, rather than 
      a singular, fixed being, narrative or moment in time.</em></p>

	  <p><em>“A feat of research and craft, this new work is a spellbinding inquiry into editing and juxtaposition; a collage one can unthread 
		allowing the viewer to discover hidden stories through familiar images. The soundtrack is performed live, made up from hundreds of preexisting 
		songs, as well as particular sounds from the original film clips.” — Flatpack Film Festival</em></p>

		<p>Photo: Joe Derhardt</p>

		<p><strong>Daniel Menche</strong> is an abstract sound artist from Portland, Oregon.  He says of his music that its “…intent is to destroy 
		all rationalized thought processes to make room for the emotional and sensual impulses to take over… The greater the intent, the greater 
		the intensity, and intensity is based upon the blood rising in speed and heat through our bodies.”</p>
		
		<p><a href="http://iklectikartlab.com/tickets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can buy tickets here</a></p></p>]]></description>
		<link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-iklectik-22nd-june-2019.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-iklectik-22nd-june-2019.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May 25th, 2019</pubDate>		
	</item>
      
          <item>
         <title>Touch Live at Iklectik | 28th April 2019</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/iklectik280419.jpg" /></p>
         <p>UnicaZürn</br>
		Mark Van Hoen</br>
		Touch</p>

		<p>Doors: 7pm<br>
		Film*: 730pm<br>
		Concert: 8pm</p>

<p>*Film: Stargazers Assistant - Resurgam II (An Audio Visual work by The Stargazer’s Assistant and Maurice Burns). Taken from the 2018 LP Resurgam I, Resurgam II by The Stargazer’s Assistant. Duration: 19mins 52sec</p>

<p>The Stargazer’s Assistant is:<br>
David J. Smith<br>
David J. Knight<br>
Michael J. York</p>

<p><a href="http://buytickets.at/iklectik/243859" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tickets</a></p>
<p><a href="https://iklectikartlab.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iklectikartlab.com</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-ik…-28th-april-2019.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-ik…-28th-april-2019.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on November 28th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
         
                  <item>
         <title>TO:112 | Simon Scott "Soundings"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>CD, Cassette &amp; Download - 8 tracks (or 2 x cassette mix) - 67 minutes</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Hodos</br>
   2. Sakura</br>
	3. Santori</br>
	4. Mae</br>
	5. Grace</br>
	6. Nigh</br>
	7. Bavaal</br>
	8. Apricity</br>
	9. Live at The Jazz Café (bonus track not on CD or cassette)</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TO112.jpg" /></p>

<p>(he previously released the live album ‘Floodlines’ in 2016 and re-issued “Below Sea Level” in 2017), finds Simon Scott, 
the composer and sound ecologist, using field recordings from various cities around the globe; modular synthesizer treatments; 
live strings and laptop electronics to create an album of transition and shifting time zones. The recordings were edited 
and composed in hotels rooms across the world as Scott was constantly on tour as the drummer for Slowdive, who successfully 
reformed in 2014.</p>

<p>Hodos, the album opener, begins with 85 mph Storm Barney recordings, ending with the fading sounds of bellbirds and cicadas 
recorded in Brisbane 2018. “I took a home recording I made of Storm Barney in Cambridge, listening to it on repeat when I was 
flying from continent to continent. I wanted this to be the starting point of the process of musically documenting how much 
travelling I was doing”. This album was created from the US to Asia, South America to Europe and the Arctic Circle back to 
the UK via California. “Working in hotel rooms and on flights, listening to and editing the recordings I’d made from all of 
these distant cities formed the basis of the album. It’s the soundtrack to four years of my life in flux with constant change, 
jet lag, excitement and the seeming perpetual motion of travelling”.</p>

<p><a href="https://simonscott.bandcamp.com/album/soundings" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to pre-order the CD from Bandcamp now</a></p>
<p><a href="https://simonscott.bandcamp.com/album/soundings-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to pre-order the Cassette from Bandcamp now</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.simonscott.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.simonscott.org</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/to112-simon-scott-soundings-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/to112-simon-scott-soundings-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 9th, 2019</pubDate>
      </item>
      
            <item>
         <title>Tone 66 | Anthony Moore "Arithmetic in the Dark"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Download album - 10 tracks - 67 minutes</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Switched</br>
   2. Particulates</br>
	3. Synthi AKS waves</br>
	4. Spinturn</br>
	5. Entangled</br>
	6. A chime of psalters</br>
	7. Hoedown</br>
	8. The psaltery sea</br>
	9. A likely outcome</br>
	10. Arithmetic in the dark</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE66.jpg" /></p>

<p>I like to imagine a time and place where arithmetic is done in a natural way by simply experiencing the unique possibility offered by sound, that of distinguishing simultaneous differences; the non-displacing waves of either AND both. 
Despite the observations of cool cats like Bill Sethares on the subjective nature of the octave´s perception, one fact remains  unfailingly true. An octave is a doubling of frequency – the higher octave has exactly twice the number of vibrations 
per second than the lower. I am imagining a planet without the invention of writing, even of symbols and scratchings in the sand where, on hearing the sound of a child and an adult singing together, a listener is doing a multiplication by two 
in a mathematics without signs; arithmetic in the dark.</p>

<p>The album consists of a set of 10 works which focus on repetition and change. The pieces evolve mostly through the active perception of the listener. Saccades and oto-acoustic emissions are evidence that perception is far from passive reception. 
The transmitting ear determines much about what it takes in.  [Anthony Moore, Arles, November 2018]</p>

<p><a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to order from the TouchShop now</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.howlround.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.reflectionsonsound.com</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/tone-66-anthony-…etic-in-the-dark.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/tone-66-anthony-…etic-in-the-dark.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on January 21st, 2019</pubDate>
      </item>
      
        <item>
         <title>Touch Live at Iklectik | 1st February 2019</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/Touch-Iklectik-Jan-19-1-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="585"  />

<p>UnicaZürn | Howlround | Touch</p>

<p><a href="http://buytickets.at/iklectik/221119" rel="noopener" target="_blank">You can buy tickets here</a></p>

<p><a href="https://iklectikartlab.com" rel="noopener" target="_blank">iklectikartlab.com</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-iklectik-1st-february-2019.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-iklectik-1st-february-2019.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on December 11th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>TO:108 | Howlround "The Debatable Lands"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Vinyl LP - 4 tracks - 32:59</p>
<p>+ 6 bonus tracks</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>Side A</br>
   1. Threip 11:53</br>
   2. The Black Path 5:21</p>

<p>Side B</br>
   3. Talkin Tarn 8:23</br>
   4. Moat 7:22</p>

<p>Bonus Tracks - free with vinyl purchase:</br>
   5. Cloven Stone</br>
   6. Dungeon Ghyll</br>
   7. Aira Force</br>
   8. a-melt-saetr</br>
   9. Carling Knott</br>
   10. Blea</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TO108.jpg" /></p>

<p>In December 2017, Howlround (Robin the Fog) was invited to perform at “The Winter Solstice Soundscapes” event for the recently opened record store “Vinyl Café” 
in his home town of Carlisle, Cumbria. Inspired by the reception to his first ever performance in the great border city, he covered his parent’s dining room table 
with the same equipment, stretched loops of tape around his mum’s seasonal candlesticks when she wasn’t looking… and this LP is the result. The only equipment used 
on the album is two 1/4” reel-to-reel tape machines and one microphone. The sounds created are entirely at the discretion of the machines (much of them derived from 
‘closed-input’ recordings) and all tracks were produced in a single take. There are no edits, no overdubs and no additional effects.</p>

<p>This marks a new, heavier direction for Howlround, a project better known for more ambient work. Described as 'Tapeloop Techno’, thick knotty tangles of dense, 
pulsating bass are an echo of Robin’s early days making bad dance music, while the abrasive snarls of feedback swirling around these tracks point to his more recent 
embrace of indeterminacy and chance composition. Previous vinyl releases on Psyché Tropes, The Wormhole, A Year in the Country and Front &amp; Follow as well as his 
own label The Fog Signals have shown a deep understanding of the possibilities of tape manipulation. On The Debatable Lands Howlround eschews the usual field recordings 
in favour of exploring the interior world of the machines themselves.</p>

<p><a href="https://touchshop.org//product_info.php?products_id=863" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to order from the TouchShop now</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.howlround.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.howlround.co.uk</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/to108-howlround-the-debatable-lands-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/to108-howlround-the-debatable-lands-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on November 30th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
               <item>
         <title>Touch presents... Live at Coaxial | 6th December 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/Coaxial-Touch-presents-6.12.18-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="585" /></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-coaxial-6th-december-2018.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-coaxial-6th-december-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on November 28th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Jóhann Jóhannsson Memorial Tribute Concert</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><Watch this church concert and tribute to Jóhann Jóhannsson.</p>

<p>A complete live performance of <a href="https://touch33.net/catalogue/to52-johann-johannsson-englaborn.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">‘Virðulegu Forsetar’</a>, Jóhann Jóhannsson's second album, which we released in 2004, following his debut <a href="https://touch33.net/catalogue/to52-johann-johannsson-englaborn.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">‘Englabörn’</a>.

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wnOMjw3jHZc">Watch here</a></p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/johann-johannsson-memorial-tribute-concert.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/johann-johannsson-memorial-tribute-concert.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on November 11th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>New Strafe FR Videos on Youtube</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/StrafeFRYouTube.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="424" /></p>

<p>Strafe F.R have added 8 videos to Touch's Youtube channel, a new spin on
<a href="https://touch33.net/news/to110-strafe-f-r-the-bird-was-stolen-2.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">‘The Bird Was Stolen’ (Touch TO:110)</a> CD.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-ksUES3XQOFheQdrSycKDQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Watch them here</a></p>

<p>All the videos were made and edited by Strafe F.R. with absolutely no use of material available online, and thus there are no credits.</p>

<p>Some remarks about the animals that appear… The spider was caught by a
member of STRAFE F.R. in Romania and was subsequently set free unharmed after filming. The dog ‘eating STRAFE F.R.’ was fed with edible paper. The writing was made with food colouring.</p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/new-strafe-fr-videos-on-youtube.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/new-strafe-fr-videos-on-youtube.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on October 31st, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
        <item>
         <title>Jóhann Jóhannsson: Unique church concert and tribute to an acclaimed Icelandic composer</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>JÓHANN JÓHANNSSON</p>

<p>Icelandic composer Jóhann Jóhannsson is widely known for his film soundtracks, including the acclaimed ‘The Theory of Everything’, for which he won a Golden Globe and was nominated for Oscar, BAFTA and Grammy awards.</p>

<p>His tried and tested combination of classical compositions with electronic music was to be heard on highly-praised albums; his debut ‘Englabörn’ (Touch, 2002), ‘Virðulegu Forsetar’ (Touch, 2004), ‘IBM 1401, A User’s Manual’ (4AD, 2006), ‘Fordlândia’ (4AD, 2008) and more recently ‘Orphée’ (DM, 2016).</p>

<p>Jóhannsson passed away unexpectedly earlier this year, in his apartment in Berlin, at the age of 48.

<p><a href="https://www.abconcerts.be/en/agenda/events/in-remembrance-of-johann-johannsson-virulegu-forsetar/20870/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.abconcerts.be/en/agenda/events/in-remembrance-of-johann-johannsson-virulegu-forsetar/20870/</a></p>

<p>TRIBUTE: IN REMEMBRANCE OF JÓHANN JÓHANNSSON</p>

<p>Together with Adam Wiltzie (A Winged Victory for the Sullen, Stars of the Lid), a close friend, and under the approving eye of Jóhannsson’s management, great care has been taken in selecting a programme, line-up, location and date. Touch is honoured to have been invited to provide the soundtrack (live) either side of the main event.</p>

<p>THE PROGRAMME: ‘VIRÐULEGU FORSETAR’</p>

<p>On the programme: a complete performance of ‘Virðulegu Forsetar’, Jóhann Jóhannsson's second album, which was released in 2004 as the successor to his debut ‘Englabörn’. ‘Virðulegu Forsetar’ means as much as ‘eminent presidents’ and also served at the time as soundtrack for an expo about … euh … presidents. ‘Virðulegu Forsetar’ is a stately, minimalistic composition in four parts with a duration of about 60 minutes. The instrumentation consists of 11 brass players, percussion, organ and piano. Until now, the album has only been performed live twice (The first was at Ultima, Oslo and then in the famous Hallgrímskirkja, Reykjavik, the place where Jóhann’s funeral was held.)</p>

<p>THE LOCATION: THE CHURCH OF SAINT JOHN THE BAPTIST AT THE BÉGUINAGE

<p>For the location of the concert, it was a deliberate choice to opt for a church, and then specifically the Church of Saint John The Baptist at the Béguinage. No coincidence, as Adam Wiltzie fell for the acoustics there after a previous successful concert with his band Stars of the Lid.</p>

<p>LINE-UP

<p>Adam Wiltzie (electro/organ) – who is also to be heard on diverse soundtracks by Jóhannsson – put together the line-up with the greatest of care. Although it is still a work in progress, aside from Wiltzie, Skúli Sverrisson (bass/electro) and conductor Guðni Franzson will join the band. Both were to be heard on ‘Virðulegu Forsetar’. Belgian Brass was selected for the wind instruments, they had already been invited by Jóhannsson for the live performance of his album ‘The Miners’ Hymns’ (130701, 2011).</p>

<p>DATE: 19.09.2018

<p>There’s no such thing as coincidence, as even the date has been chosen with care. On September 19 Jóhannsson would have turned 49</p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/johann-johannsson-unique-church-concert-and-tribute-to-an-acclaimed-icelandic-filmcomposer.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/johann-johannsson-unique-church-concert-and-tribute-to-an-acclaimed-icelandic-filmcomposer.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on September 20th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Tone 65 Jana Winderen - "Spring Bloom in the Marginal Ice Zone"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>CD - 3 tracks - 77:49</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Interview with Carlos Duarte 5:48</br>
2. Spring Bloom in the Marginal Ice Zone - Headphones mix 37:00</br>
3. Spring Bloom in the Marginal Ice Zone - Speakers mix 35:00</p>

<p><a href="https://touchshop.org/media/SpringBloomDuarteExerpt.wav">You can listen an extract here</a></p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE65.jpg" /></p>

<pThe marginal ice zone is the dynamic border between the open sea and the sea ice, which is ecologically extremely vulnerable. The phytoplankton present in the sea produces half of the oxygen on the planet. During spring, this zone is the most important CO2 sink in our biosphere. In Spring Bloom in the Marginal Ice Zone the sounds of the living creatures become a voice in the current political debate concerning the official definition of the location of the ice edge.</p>

<p>The listener experiences the bloom of plankton, the shifting and crackling sea ice in the Barents Sea around Spitsbergen, towards the North Pole, and the underwater sounds made by bearded seals, migrating species such as humpbacks and orcas, and the sound made by hunting saithe, crustaceans and spawning cod, all depending on the spring bloom.</p>

<p>Spring Bloom in the Marginal Ice Zone is a Sonic Acts and Dark Ecology commission first shown as a 7 channel installation at the Sonic Acts festival (Muziekgebouw, Amsterdam, 2017). It was supported by Art &amp; Technology - Arts Council Norway, Fond for lyd og bilde, Tono stipendet, ARCEx research cruise on R/V Helmer Hanssen, UiT The Arctic University of Norway. Thanks to Paul Wassmann, Ingrid Wiedmann, Britt Kramvig, Berit Kristoffersen, Hilde Methi, Annette Wolfsberger, North Sailing, Arctic Encounters, Mamont Foundation &amp; TBA21 Academy.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.kaust.edu.sa/en/study/faculty/carlos-duarte" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CARLOS M. DUARTE</a> is Professor of Marine Science, Tarek Ahmed Juffali Research Chair in Red Sea Ecology, Biological and Environmental Science and Engineering Division, and is a world-wide leader in multiple branches of biological oceanography and marine ecology.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.npolar.no/en/people/philipp.assmy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PHILIPP ASSMY</a> is a researcher at The Norwegian Polar Institute, Tromsø, Norway. Current activities include species-specific studies of planktonic and sympagic communities and primary productivity in the Arctic Ocean north of Svalbard. He is also studying the impact of changing sea ice conditions and associated effects (e.g. changes in light climate and surface stratification) on phytoplankton and ice algal communities.</p>

<p>Artwork &amp; photography by Jon Wozencroft</br>
Booklet photography by Philipp Assmy</br>
Mastered by Denis Blackham, Skye</p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/catalogue/tone-65-jana-winderen-spring-bloom-in-the-marginal-ice-zone.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/catalogue/tone-65-jana-winderen-spring-bloom-in-the-marginal-ice-zone.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on September 19th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
            <item>
         <title>TO:106 | Ipek Gorgun - "ECCE HOMO"</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>CD + full album download - 11 tracks - 47:06</p>

<p>Release date: 7th September 2018</p>

<p>Ecce Homo explores the lighter and darker shades of the human psyche, behaviour and existence, and humanity's ability to create beauty and destruction. What lies in the essence of such complexity has become a core idea for the album, while Gorgun seeks to figure out if there is a true meaning to being human, and human being. Starting with “Neroli” as a human fascination with nature and finalising with “To Cross Great Rivers”; the album reflects the contemplations of a spectator being exposed to the human civilization, and witnessing human activity, including his/her own. Trying to acquire a glimpse of the various layers of human flesh and bones, the sound of the album aims to present a diversity of the sonic spectrum, with tracks varying between ambient and noisy landscapes.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TO106.jpg" /></p>

<p>Track Titles:</p>

<p>1. Neroli - <a href="http://touchshop.org/media/Neroli.mp3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">you can listen to this track here</a></br>
2. Afterburner</br>
3. Tserin Dopchut</br>
4. Le Sacre l</br>
5. Le Sacre ll</br>
6. Bohemian Grove</br>
7. Seneca</br>
8. Knightscope K5</br>
9. Reverance</br>
10. Mileva</br>
11. To Cross Great Rivers</br></p>

<p>All tracks recorded and mixed by Ipek Gorgun, Istanbul 2016 - 2018</br>
Mastered by Denis Blackham @ Skye</br>
Photography &amp; design by Jon Wozencroft</br></p>

<p>Pitchfork: "The Turkish sound artist balances technical precision, emotional potency, and trenchant cultural critique on an album whose individual sounds are as compelling as their widescreen narratives."</p>

<p>Beach Sloth: "A truly unusual and downright beautiful intersection of the experimental and emotional, Ipek Gorgun’s “Ecce Homo” is a true triumph."</p>

<p><a href="https://touchshop.org//product_info.php?products_id=855" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>You can read all reviews here</em></a></p>

<p>Artist Biography</p>

<p>Ipek Gorgun is an electronic music composer currently enrolled in the doctoral program of Sonic Arts at Istanbul Technical University's Center for Advanced Studies in Music. After graduating from Bilkent University with a degree in Political Science, she completed her Master's studies in Philosophy at Galatasaray University. As one of the participants of the Red Bull Music Academy in 2014, she performed in Tokyo as an opening artist for Ryoji Ikeda’s “Test Pattern No: 6” and joined Otomo Yoshidide for a collective improvisation project. As a bass player and vocalist for projects and bands such as Bedroomdrunk and Vector Hugo between 2001-2013, she also performed in an opening gig for Jennifer Finch from L7 and Simon Scott from Slowdive, as well as performing live with David Brown from Brazzaville. She has released two EPs with Bedroomdrunk, entitled “This is What Happened (2003)” and “Raw (2007)”. Besides group projects and solo performances, she also composed the soundtrack for the documentary ‘Yok Anasinin Soyadi (Mrs. His Name) directed by Hande Cayir in 2012, portraying Turkish women’s struggle for keeping their original surnames after marriage. Her debut album Aphelion was self-released in February, 2016 and is reissued by Touch in December, under the TOUCHLINE catalogue. In 2017 she released a collaborative album from Halocline Trance, with Canadian producer Ceramic TL (aka Egyptrixx) entitled “Perfect Lung”, and a mini-album with the Italian electroacoustic duo, Alberi. Aside from many performances following these albums, she also performed in Sonar Istanbul (2017), BBC Radio 3’s “Open Ear” at LSO St. Luke’s (2018) and opened for the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra in Oggimusica Acousmonium with an electronic rework of Igor Stravinsky’s “The Firebird” (2018). Ipek Gorgun also practices performance, street and abstract photography. She won the IPA honorable mention award in 2013-14 with her work entitled "Bubblegun Daydreamer" and in 2013, she worked as the advertisement photographer for Contemporary Istanbul Art fair.</p>

<p><a href="https://touchshop.org//product_info.php?products_id=855" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available to preorder from the TouchShop now</a></br>
<a href="http://http://www.ipekgorgun.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.ipekgorgun.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/to106-ipek-gorgun-ecce-homo-2.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/to106-ipek-gorgun-ecce-homo-2.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 30th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
            <item>
         <title>Touch Movements | Torino August 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/PhilipJeckTurin.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="439" />

<p>Philip Jeck transforms the space</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/SimonScottTurin.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="439" /></p>

<p>Simon Scott, in the element</p></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/touch-movements-torino-august-2018.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/touch-movements-torino-august-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 30th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                        <item>
         <title>Today's Festival, Turin, Italy | 24-26th August 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Friday 24th August
1900 <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/schedule/touch-movements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Touch Movements</a></br>
2300 Philip Jeck</br></p>

<p>Saturday 25th August</br>
1900 <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/schedule/touch-movements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Touch Movements</a></br>
2300 Simon Scott</br></p>

<p>Location: <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/plartwo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PLARTWO</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">todaysfestival.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/todays-festival-turin-italy-24-26th-august-2018.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/todays-festival-turin-italy-24-26th-august-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 14th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Sleepless, Music Center, Los Angeles | 27th July 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1130pm - 230am</p>

<p>Friday 24th August
1900 <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/schedule/touch-movements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Touch Movements</a></br>
2300 Philip Jeck</br></p>

<p>Saturday 25th August</br>
1900 <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/schedule/touch-movements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Touch Movements</a></br>
2300 Simon Scott</br></p>

<p>Location: <a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com/plartwo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PLARTWO</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.todaysfestival.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">todaysfestival.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>https://touch33.net/news/todays-festival-turin-italy-24-26th-august-2018.html</link>
         <guid>https://touch33.net/news/todays-festival-turin-italy-24-26th-august-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 14th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Sleepless, Music Center, Los Angeles | 27th July 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1130pm - 230am</p>

<p>In partnership with Fulcrum Arts, this special Sleepless: The Music Center After Hours celebrates the relationship of science and art, reimagining the role of artist as the scientist and transforming The Music Center’s Dorothy Chandler Pavilion in powerful new ways.

Explore the intersection of science and art, as this distinct Sleepless connects the two disciplines in a dynamic evening featuring exhibitions, performance art, live music performances, DJ sets, installations and more. Stay up and discover the art of science.</p>

<p>1. Field Recording Exhibition</p>
<p>Dial in to hear field recordings from Chris Watson and Jana Winderen at the Sleepless Phone Booths.</p>

<p>2. Slow Sound</p>
<p>Plug into this headphone experience with live sets from <a href="https://www.thezacharypaul.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zachary Paul</a> and <a href="http://www.jasminblasco.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jasmin Blasco</a>.</p>

<p>Curated by <a href="https://www.fulcrumarts.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fulcrum Arts</a></p>

<p>https://www.musiccenter.org/tickets/events-by-the-music-center/sleepless/</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/sleepless-music-center-los-angeles-27th-july-2018.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/sleepless-music-center-los-angeles-27th-july-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on July 14th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
                  <item>
         <title>Touch presents... Live at Coaxial, Los Angeles | 4th August 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/Coaxial-Touch-Presents-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="585" />

<p><a href="http://www.markvanhoen.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Van Hoen</a></p>
<p>Geneva Skeen</p>
<p><a href="http://thezacharypaul.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zachary Paul</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.field.nu/roughmusic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rough music</a></p>

<p>Doors at 7pm Show starts promptly at 8pm</p>

<p><a href="http://coaxialarts.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coaxial</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-coaxial-los-angeles-4th-august-2018.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-at-coaxial-los-angeles-4th-august-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on July 13th, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Touch Presents... Live in Berlin | 20th June 2018</title>
         
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Touch Presents...</p>
<p>Doors: 21:00 Start: 21:00</p>

<p><em>Mark Van Hoen</em></p>
<p>Mark Van Hoen is a British electronic music artist. He has just released his new solo album, <a href="https://markvanhoen.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">"Invisible Threads"</a> on Touch. Pitchfork said, "Musically, Van Hoen belongs to a distinguished family tree. Originally influenced by the likes of Brian Eno and Tangerine Dream, and later presaging both Autechre's glitch and Boards of Canada's pastoral IDM.”
<a href="https://markvanhoen.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">markvanhoen.bandcamp.com/</a>
<a href="http://www.markvanhoen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.markvanhoen.com/</a></p>

<p><em>Sohrab </em></p>
<p>Sohrab was born in Tehran in 1984. He was seven when the Iran-Iraq war ended. His name, from an old poem called ‘Shahname’, means ‘rouge water’, which can also mean ‘blood’. He started a punk band with his brother and a friend, which lasted about two years before splitting… He was totally isolated in Iran, so he left (if only it was that easy) and now resides in Germany.
<a href="http://touch33.net/artists/sohrab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">touch33.net/artists/sohrab</a></p>

<p><em>Jasmin Blasco </em></p>
<p>Jasmin Blasco (b.1981) is a multi-disciplinary artist who approaches time-based media as the site where sound, image, and language conspire to generate fictions. Through a process of research and abstraction, his practice stages the individual in problematic narratives. He lives and works in Los Angeles.
<a href="http://jasminblasco.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jasminblasco.com/</a></p>

<p><em>Marta De Pascalis</em></p>
<p>Marta De Pascalis (Rome, 1987) is an Italian composer living and working in Berlin. Her solo works employ analog synthesis and tape loops, incorporating free playing into steady, repetitive patterns. She has produced two albums of Berlin School minimal synth excursions: the self-released Quitratue (2014) and Anzar (The Tapeworm, 2016). Her new piece ‘Her Core’ will be published on spring 2018 by The Wormhole.
<a href="http://www.martadepascalis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.martadepascalis.com/</a></p>

<p><em>++DJ v93r </em></p>
<p><em>++++Secret special guest</em></p>

<p><a href="https://bit.ly/2M6o5lW" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tickets</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.kottimonarch.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Monarch</a></p>]]></description>

         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-in-berlin-20th-june-2018.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch-presents-live-in-berlin-20th-june-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on June 7, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
      
<item>
         <title>Touch Live at Iklectik | 23rd March 2018</title>
         
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/Iklectik-1.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>
         
         <p>This show is now sold out

<p><a href="http://www.philipjeck.com">Philip Jeck</a> - <a href="http://www.yannnovak.com">Yann Novak</a> - <a href="http://www.simonscott.org">Simon Scott</a></p>
<p>Touch</p>]]></description>
<p><a href="http://www.iklectikartlab.com">Iklectik</a></p>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-ik…-23rd-march-2018.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch-live-at-ik…-23rd-march-2018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March 23, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Is 36 Today</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Today, 11th March, is the official 36th anniversary of the founding of Touch in 1982...</p>

<p><span class="smallpic"><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/245x/soulkitchen.jpg" /></span></p>

<p>First contact with New Order after their concert at the Newcastle Mayfair on 11th March 1982…</p>

<p><a href="http://touch33.net/full-catalogue-by-date">You can follow our progress year by year here...</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_is_36_today.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_is_36_today.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March 11, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 60 | Touch Presents... - &quot;Live at Human Resources&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/Tone60.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>
         
         <p>Download only - 9 tracks - <a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-human-resources" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available from the Touch Bandcamp page</a></p>

<p>Release date: 1st March 2018</p>

<p>February 23rd @ Human Resources, Los Angeles, USA<br />
Curated by Mike Harding &amp; Yann Novak</p>

<p>To launch the release of Yann Novak’s second album for Touch, a live event was held at Human Resources on 23rd February in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>The evening also included a tribute to Jóhann Jóhannsson by the ensemble</p>

<p>"Inspired use of @Bandcamp by @touchmusic - presenting last Friday's #gigoftheyear to a global audience less than a week after @yannnovak &amp; co (@robertcrouch @JasminBlasco @garekjondruss @_jakemuir @geneeves @byronwestbrook)'s "absorbing &amp; immersive salon"" (Lend Me Your Ears)</p>

<p>Touch Presents…</p>

<p>Jasmin Blasco<br />
Robert Crouch<br />
Garek Druss<br />
Jake Muir<br />
Yann Novak<br />
Zachary Paul<br />
Geneva Skeen<br />
Byron Westbrook</p>

<p>You can read about the event here - <a href="http://artculturejazz.com/yann-novak-album-release-at-human-resources">artculturejazz.com/yann-novak-album-release-at-human-resources</a></p>

<p>Photo: Jon Wozencroft, Kew Gardens, London</p>

</div>
<a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-human-resources" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available from the Touch Bandcamp page</a>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_60_touch_presents_live_at.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_60_touch_presents_live_at.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March  2, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Jon Wozencroft is In Wild Air</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Jon Wozencroft is a Senior Tutor at the <a href="https://www.rca.ac.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Royal College of Art</a> responsible for sound, moving image and photography on the Visual Communication programme, with an emphasis on interdisciplinary structures. He holds monthly, cross-college, sound seminars that explore the invisible aspects of art and design practice.</p>

<p><a href="https://mailchi.mp/42b0eda17d1c/jon-wozencroft-is-in-wild-air" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mailchi.mp/42b0eda17d1c/jon-wozencroft-is-in-wild-air</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/jon_wozencroft_is_in_wild_air.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/jon_wozencroft_is_in_wild_air.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 26, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>TO:105 | Yann Novak - &quot;The Future is a Forward Escape into the Past&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TO105.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>
         
         <p>CD - 4 tracks - 41:28<br />
Gatefold ekopak + full album download</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Radical Transparency<br />
2. The Inertia of Time<br />
3. Casting Ourselves Back into the Past<br />
4. Nothing Ever Transcends its Immediate Environment</p>

<p>All tracks composed and recorded by Yann Novak in Los Angeles 2017<br />
Vocal sample on "Nothing Ever Transcends its Immediate Environment" by Geneva Skeen<br />
Photography &amp; design by Jon Wozencroft<br />
Mastered by Lawrence English at 158</p>

<p>‘The Future is a Forward Escape Into the Past’ is the latest album by Los Angeles-based multidisciplinary artist and composer Yann Novak, and his second for Touch. It considers the relationships between memory, time, and context through four vibrantly constructed tracks that push Novak’s work in a new direction while simultaneously exploring his sonic past. ‘The Future is a Forward Escape Into the Past’ is composed as a quadriptych – a single gesture broken into four parts – that meditates on the inevitable progression of time, our relationship to the past, and our distortion of the past through the imperfections of memory. The album will be released February 23, 2018 on the London-based label Touch. Available digitally and on CD, the physical version will be packaged in a gatefold sleeve as a limited edition of 500. For more information on the artist and release, please visit www.touch33.net.</p>

<p>The album’s conceptual roots stem from ‘The Archaic Revival’ by American ethnobotanist and psychonaut Terence McKenna. In it, McKenna theorizes that when a culture becomes dysfunctional it attempts to revert back to a saner moment in its own history. He suggested that abstract expressionism, body piercing and tattooing, psychedelic drug use, sexual permissiveness, and rave culture were proof of this default to a more primal time. The text’s idealism was influential to Novak in the ‘90s, but today the theory bears a darkly-veiled resemblance to the rise of nostalgia-driven nationalism. Regardless of whether one agrees or disagrees with the signifiers of a ‘better time’ – McKenna’s idea highlights our propensity for selective memory, seeing history through the lens of memory instead of fact. On ‘The Future is a Forward Escape Into the Past’ Novak looked back at his own older works through this lens as inspiration.</p>

<p>“For this album I was interested in expanding into a more emotive compositional style and palette. In doing so, I was reminded that this was territory I had covered early on in my career — the whole process became a way to reconnect with my own past and history.”</p>

<p>The Album’s four tracks dynamically shift and surge, where time is rendered as material and momentum compels it into movement. Subtle distortion throughout the album ties the tracks together and echoes techniques explored in Novak’s ‘Meadowsweet’ (Dragon’s Eye, 2006). Tension gives way to a halcyon vision of place in “Radical Transparency,” immediately followed by the austere swells of “The Inertia of Time,” a piece that captures the twin impulse of generating optimistic beauty in harshly muted tones. Both tracks introduce subtle bass swells and stabs reminiscent of ‘In Residence’ (Dragon’s Eye, 2008). From there, the album grows darker with “Casting Ourselves Back into the Past,” and “Nothing Ever Transcends its Immediate Environment,” two icier tracks that preserve the album’s core: a layer of something long since passed that locks us into the very moment we inhabit. The latter introduces a processed vocal sample of Geneva Skeen, similar to Novak’s collaborative work with Marc Manning on ‘Pairings’ (Dragon’s Eye, 2007). The album is a study in perception and alteration, manipulation and awareness, effectively capturing Novak’s command of emotional texturing.</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=15&amp;products_id=843">Pre-order Yann Novak - "The Future is a Forward Escape into the Past" [CD + Download] in the TouchShop</a><a href="http://www.yannovak.com"><br />
</a><a href="http://www.yannnovak.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.yannnovak.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/to105_yann_novak_the_future_is.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/to105_yann_novak_the_future_is.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 24, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Presents... Live in Los Angeles | 23rd February 2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/HR-Feb23-Poster.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>

<p>February 23rd @ <a href="http://humanresourcesla.com/event/the-future-is-a-forward-escape-into-the-past/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Human Resources</a>, Los Angeles, USA<br />
<em>Curated by Mike Harding &amp; Yann Novak</em></p>

<p>To launch the release of Yann Novak's second album for Touch, a live event will be held at Human Resources on 23rd February in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Touch Presents…<br />
Jasmin Blasco<br />
Robert Crouch<br />
Garek Druss<br />
Jake Muir<br />
Yann Novak<br />
Zachary Paul<br />
Geneva Skeen<br />
Byron Westbrook</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=15&amp;products_id=843">Pre-order Yann Novak - "The Future is a Forward Escape into the Past" [CD + Download] in the TouchShop</a><a href="http://www.yannovak.com"><br />
</a><a href="http://www.yannnovak.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.yannnovak.com</a></p>

<p><a href="http://humanresourcesla.com/event/the-future-is-a-forward-escape-into-the-past/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">humanresourcesla.com/event/the-future-is-a-forward-escape-into-the-past/</a><br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/164373797520853/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.facebook.com/events/164373797520853/</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_presents_live_in_los_ang_3.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_presents_live_in_los_ang_3.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 22, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Jóhann Jóhannsson 1969-2018</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/englaborn.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>
         
         <p>The news that Jóhann Jóhannsson has died hits hard. He configured a personal and progressive spirit, making a bridge between experimental music and Hollywood, for whom success was always subjugated to a humble awareness. Above everything he was a friend, a lovely person to work with. In his short career, he changed the way the world thinks about alternative music, then film soundtracks, and had this exceptional talent to merge classicism with noise and disturbance.</p>

<p>But to start earlier than Friday’s appalling news…</p>

<p>In Summer 2002 we finished production for Jóhann’s first release for Touch, his first outside Iceland and the Kitchen Motors project – “Englabörn”. It was Andrew McKenzie, the two of them still living in Iceland, who introduced us and encouraged us to release it. Jóhann is on record as saying how much he owed to McKenzie’s presence in Iceland, being an education and catalyst for his work. Then, in turn, it was Jóhann who suggested we work with Hildur Guðnadóttir and so a continuing light shines through our story.</p>

<p>The situation changes, ambitions become unaffordable financially, so it was part of the sequence that Jóhann moved into the next dimension, first recording for 4AD and being supported by Forma for live events, and latterly recording for Deutsche Grammaphon and winning multiple awards.</p>

<p>While he only released his first two albums with us (“Englabörn” in 2002 and two years later, “Virthulega Forsetar”), Jóhann always remained close to our operations, contributing new compositions to "Touch 25" in 2006 and the more recent “Touch Movements”. One of our favourite moments was when he expressed his joy after a live performance of “Virthulega Forsetar” at Ultima, Oslo in 2005. All who were there will never forget it – or him.</p>

<p>Jóhann’s work has made a huge impact on various films, we don’t need to list them here. We remember his sensitive soul… His dedication. It is easily heard, in the great work which will last beyond a lifetime.</p>

<p>[Photo: Front cover for "Englabörn" CD and vinyl editions. Taken in Sicily in April 2001, the Strait of Messina. To be rereleased as "Englabörn Variations" by Deutsche Grammaphon later in 2018.]</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/johann_johannsson_19692018.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/johann_johannsson_19692018.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 11, 2018</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Philip Jeck &amp; Claire M Singer, Live at Meakusma | Belgium 9-11th September 2017</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Touch Presents…</p>

<p><a href="http://www.philipjeck.com" target="_blank">Philip Jeck</a><br />
<a href="http://www.clairemsinger.com" target="_blank">Claire M Singer</a><br />
<a href="http://spire.org.uk/category/the-eternal-chord/" target="_blank">The Eternal Chord</a></p>

<p>The Friedenskirche, a church in Eupen, will be host to the “Touch Presents…” program, featuring two organ concerts by Claire M. Singer and The Eternal Chord and a live performance by Philip Jeck. Claire M. Singer’s 2016 debut Solas spans 14 years of her work in acoustic and electronic composition. Together with Mike Harding, she is also a member of The Eternal Chord, a project that focuses on the sonic power of the organ. Philip Jeck started working with record players and electronic instrumentation in the 80s and is renowned for his soundtracks, music for theatre and dance companies and solo concert work.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.meakusma.org/event/meakusma-festival-2017/" target="_blank">www.meakusma.org</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/philip_jeck_claire_m_singer_li.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/philip_jeck_claire_m_singer_li.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on September  1, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 58 | Philip Jeck - &quot;Iklectik&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TONE58-2.jpg" alt="" width="585" /></p>
         
         <p>CD and download - 1 track</p>

<p>Release date: 22nd September 2017</p>

<p>Artwork and photography by Jon Wozencroft<br />
Recorded and mastered by Jeff Ardron of St. Austral Sound</p>

<p>The 6th in the series of limited edition compact disc live recordings (after Thomas Köner & Jana Winderen, Simon Scott, Bethan Kellough, Yann Novak, Robert Crouch) brings Philip Jeck live at Iklectik, London.</p>

<p>Philip Jeck studied visual arts at Dartington College of Arts in the 1970’s and has been creating sound with record-players since the early 80’s. He has worked with many dance and theatre companies and played with muscians/composers such as Jah Wobble, Steve Lacy, Gavin Bryars, Jaki Liebezeit, David Sylvian, Sidsel Endresen and Bernhard Lang.</p>

<p>He has released 11 solo albums, the most recent “Cardinal”, a double vinyl release on Touch. “Suite”, another vinyl-only release, won a Distinction at The Prix Ars Electronica, and a cassette release on The Tapeworm, “Spool”, playing only bass guitar. His CD “Sand” (2008) was 2nd in The Wire’s top 50 of the year. His largest work made with Lol Sargent, “Vinyl Requiem” was for 180 record-players, 9 slide-projectors and 2 16mm movie-projectors. It received a Time Out Performance Award. Vinyl Coda I-III, a commission from Bavarian Radio in 1999 won the Karl Sczuka Foderpreis for Radio Art.</p>

<p>Philip also still works as a visual artist, usually incorporating sound and has shown installations at The Bluecoat, Liverpool, Hayward Gallery, London, The Hamburger Bahnhof Gallery, Berlin, ZKM in Karlsruhe and The Shanghai and Liverpool Bienalles.</p>

<p>Philip Jeck has won the Paul Hamlyn Foundation Award for Composers 2009. A presentation ceremony took place at The Royal Institute of British Architects, London, on 9th November 2009.</p>

<p>He has toured in an Opera North production playing live to the silent movie Pandora’s Box (composed by Hildur Gudnadottir and Johann Johannson).He has also worked again with Gavin Bryars on a composition “Pneuma” for a ballet choreographed by Carolyn Carlson for The Opera de Bordeaux and has recently made and performed the sound for “The Ballad of Ray & Julie” at the Everyman Theatre, Liverpool.</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=15&products_id=817">Pre-order Philip Jeck - "Iklectik" [CD + Download] in the TouchShop</a><a href="http://www.philipjeck.com"><br />
<a href="http://www.philipjeck.com" target="new">www.philipjeck.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_58_philip_jeck_iklectik_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_58_philip_jeck_iklectik_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on September  1, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Claire M Singer - One to Watch at Spitfire Audio</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>"Unearthing more future greats, this time we meet organ revivalist, Claire M Singer.</p>

<p>Claire M Singer is a composer, producer and performer of acoustic and electronic music, film and installations. She also looks after one of the most prestigious organs in the world, the legendary 1877 Henry Willis organ at Union Chapel, London."</p>

<p><a href="https://www.spitfireaudio.com/ones-to-watch/claire-m-singer/" target="_blank">www.spitfireaudio.com/ones-to-watch/claire-m-singer/</a></p>

<p><a href="http://touch333.bandcamp.com" target="_blank">'Solas' is still available on compact disc and digital download</a> </p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/claire_m_singer_one_to_watch_a.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/claire_m_singer_one_to_watch_a.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on August 30, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Chris Watson Albums Back in Stock | &apos;El Tren Fantasma&apos; &amp; &apos;Weather Report&apos;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that two major recorded albums, '<a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=9&amp;products_id=482" target="_blank">El Tren Fantasma</a>' & '<a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=9&amp;products_id=15" target="_blank">Weather Report</a>' by <a href="http://www.chriswatson.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chris Watson</a> have been republished;</p>

<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TO42-El-Tren-Fantasma-Chris-Watson-1.png" alt="" width="585" /></p>

<p><strong>'El Tren Fantasma' [Touch # TO:42, 2011]</strong></p>

<p>“Take the ghost train from Los Mochis to Veracruz and travel cross country, coast to coast, Pacific to Atlantic. Ride the rhythm of the rails on board the Ferrocarriles Nacionales de México (FNM) and the music of a journey that has now passed into history.”</p>

<p>El Tren Fantasma, (The Ghost Train), is Chris Watson’s 4th solo album for Touch, and his first since Weather Report in 2003, which was named as one of the albums you should hear before you die in The Guardian. A Radio programme was broadcast on BBC Radio 4 on Saturday 30 Oct, 2010, produced by Sarah Blunt, and described as “a thrilling acoustic journey across the heart of Mexico from Pacific to Atlantic coast using archive recordings to recreate a rail passenger service which no longer exists. It’s now more than a decade since FNM operated its last continuous passenger service across country. Chris Watson spent a month on board the train with some of the last passengers to travel this route. As sound recordist he was part of the film crew working on a programme in the BBC TV series Great Railways Journeys. Now, in this album, the journey of the ‘ghost train’ is recreated, evoking memories of a recent past, capturing the atmosphere, rhythms and sounds of human life, wildlife and the journey itself along the tracks of one of Mexico’s greatest engineering projects.</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=9&amp;products_id=482" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This compact disc is now available to order from TouchShop</a></p>

<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TO47-Weather-Report-Chris-Watson-1.png" alt="" width="585" /></p>

<p><strong>'Weather Report' [Touch # TO:47, 2003]</strong></p>

<p>The weather has created and shaped all our habitats. Clearly it also has a profound and dynamic effect upon our lives and that of other animals. The three locations featured here all have moods and characters which are made tangible by the elements, and these periodic events are represented within by a form of time compression.</p>

<p>This was Chris’s first foray into composition using his location recordings of wildlife and habitats – previously he has been concerned with describing and revealing the special atmosphere of a place by site specific, untreated location recordings. For the first time here he constructs collages of sounds, which evolve from a series of recordings made at the specific locations over varying periods of time.</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?cPath=9&amp;products_id=15" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This compact disc is now available to order from TouchShop</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/chris_watson_albums_back_in_st.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/chris_watson_albums_back_in_st.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on July 15, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Radio 131 | Bill Thompson</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>28.06.17 - <a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio131.mp3">Bill Thompson - Live at the Brunswick Club, Bristol, June 19th 2017</a> - 31:37 - 320 kbps</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/images/Radio131.jpg" /></p>

<p>This is a two channel recording of a live solo performance using the Moog guitar plus stuff. The set was improvised and only the second time I'd performed solo with the Moog (the first being the night before in Swansea). The gig was at the Brunswick Club in Bristol which houses several arts groups including BEEF (Bristol Experimental Expanded Film) who, via sound and video artist Kathy Hinde, had invited me to perform. When I arrived in Bristol and gave the taxi driver the address, he told me that the Brunswick Club was closed down, and even if it wasn’t, he doubted I’d be performing there. Apparently it used to be a Working Man's Club frequented by taxi drivers. Not any more.</p>

<p>Equipment: Moog Guitar, ebow, shortwave radio, tone generator, guitar pedals (reverb, delay, distortion and fuzz factory), plasma and bicycle lights, a child's light wand, two vibrators, portable CD player (unplugged), modified fans, mixer, and miscelaneous debris.</p>

<p>Recorded by Kathy Hinde.</p>

<p>Subscribe to the TouchPod podcast of TouchRadio via the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=80842701">iTunes Music Store</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio131.mp3">Play "Live at the Brunswick Club, Bristol, June 19th 2017"</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.billthompson.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">billthompson.org</a><br />
<a href="http://www.touchradio.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">touchradio.org.uk</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_131_bill_thompson.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_131_bill_thompson.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on July 15, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>The Handmaid&apos;s Tale [HULU/C4]</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/circle-spirals-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="435" /></p>

<p>A significant factor in responding to the decline of the compact disc format is to find new forms of exposure for challenging music. <a href="http://www.hildurness.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hildur Gudnadottir</a>'s work for Touch, in particular "Saman", takes a central role in forming the emotional narrative of this acclaimed series, starring Elizabeth Moss, made by Hulu (USA) and now showing on Channel 4 (UK).</p>

<p>Hildur's four CD's for Touch will re-released in 2 Double-CD editions in<br />
the autumn. In the meantime, "The Handmaid's Tale" is free to view on<br />
<a href="http://www.channel4.com/programmes/catchup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Channel 4 OD</a>. We recommend it.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/the_handmaids_tale_huluc4.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/the_handmaids_tale_huluc4.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on June 28, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 51 | Thomas Köner &amp; Jana Winderen - &quot;Cloître&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Released: 16th June 2017<br />
CD - 1 track - 44:24</p>

<p>Remastered by Thomas Köner<br />
Photography &amp; design by Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TONE51.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="585" /></p>

<p><strong>Track listing:</strong></p>

<p>1. Cloître</p>

<p>Recorded live from the cloisters at Evreux Cathedral, Normandy, France by Franck Dubois, 14th June 2014, as part of <a href="http://www.lateliers.fr">L'Ateliers</a>. With thanks to Denis Boyer.</p>

<p><a href="https://touch333.bandcamp.com/album/cloitre-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pre-order Thomas Koner &amp; Jana Winderen "Cloitre" [CD + Download] on Bandcamp</a><br />
<a href="http://www.thomaskoner.com" target="new">www.thomaskoner.com</a><br />
<a href="http://www.janawinderen.com" target="new">www.janawinderen.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_51_thomas_koner_jana_wind.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_51_thomas_koner_jana_wind.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May 21, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Radio 130 | Félix Blume</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>20.05.17 - <a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio130.mp3">Félix Blume - A La Orilla (On the edge)</a> - 45:01 - 320 kbps</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/images/Radio130.jpg" /></p>

<p>On the edge of the jungle, where the Amazon Rainforest begins in southern Venezuela, where the Gran Sabana ends, humans are still trying to enter a world dominated by nature. Trees, rivers, animals and insects extend to the horizon, and the sounds reach our ears to remind us of their empire.</p>

<p>Subscribe to the TouchPod podcast of TouchRadio via the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=80842701">iTunes Music Store</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio130.mp3">Play "A La Orilla"</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.felixblume.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">felixblume.com</a><br />
<a href="http://www.touchradio.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">touchradio.org.uk</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_130_felix_blume.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_130_felix_blume.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May 20, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Jon Wozencroft on nts radio</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/ntstouch.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="433" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.nts.live/shows/knee-deep/episodes/knee-deep-22nd-april-2017">Knee Deep</a></p>

<p>NTS Radio, 22nd April 2017, 6pm-8pm<br />
Location: Dalston, London E8<br />
Presented by Mattis</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/jon_wozencroft_on_nts_radio.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/jon_wozencroft_on_nts_radio.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May 11, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 56 | Robert Crouch - &quot;Sublunar&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>CD and download - 4 tracks</p>

<p>Release date: 19th May 2017</p>

<p><img src="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TONE56585px.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="596" /></p>

<p>Written, recorded and performed by Robert Crouch<br />
Mastered by Lawrence English @ 158<br />
Artwork &amp; Photography: Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Descension<br />
2. Brick by Brick<br />
3. Listen to the sound of the earth turning<br />
4. Coda (Sailing Stones)</p>

<p>Presented live in Los Angeles. Source material originally developed as part of <em>mas gestos y mas caras</em>, a collaborative performance with Rafa Esparza and Yann Novak, presented at the Hammer Museum on July 8, 2016</p>

<p><a href="https://touchshop.org//product_info.php?products_id=808">Pre-order Robert Crouch - "Sublunar" [CD + Download] in the TouchShop</a><a href="http://www.robertcrouch.com"><br />
www.robertcrouch.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_56_robert_crouch_sublunar.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_56_robert_crouch_sublunar.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May  7, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>A Handmaid’s Tale (HULU, 2017)</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>This new series starting April 26th 2017 on HULU starring Elizabeth Moss uses some of <a href="http://www.hildurness.com" target="_blank">Hildur Gudnadottir</a>’s music… episodes 2, 3 and 9 contain tracks you can hear on <a href="http://www.hildurgudnadottir.bandcamp.com" target="_blank">her bandcamp site</a>, where you can stream and download her albums.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/a_handmaids_tale_hulu_2017.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/a_handmaids_tale_hulu_2017.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on May  7, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Radio 129 | Jana Winderen - Daybreak; Kochi (Kerala), India</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>11.04.17 - <a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio129.mp3">Jana Winderen - Daybreak; Kochi (Kerala), India</a> - 38:03 - 320 kbps</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/images/Radio129.jpg" /></p>

<p>This crepuscular recording was made from 4:45am on the 14th December 2016 in the south Indian city of Kochi. I was there to play "Drifting", a performance at Vasco da Gama Square, for Convening #2 hosted by the TBA21 Academy on the following day.</p>

<p>Subscribe to the TouchPod podcast of TouchRadio via the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=80842701">iTunes Music Store</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio129.mp3">Play "Daybreak; Kochi, Kerala, India"</a></p>

<p><a href="http://janawinderen.com" target="_blank">janawinderen.com</a><br />
<a href="http://www.touchradio.org.uk" target="_blank">touchradio.org.uk</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_129_jana_winderen.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_129_jana_winderen.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on April 12, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Radio 128 | Geneva Skeen &amp; Sarah Rara</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>23.03.17 - <a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio128.mp3">Geneva Skeen &amp; Sarah Rara - Live in Los Angeles</a> - 37:03 - 320 kbps</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/images/Radio128.jpg" /></p>

<p>Live at <a href="http://humanresourcesla.com" target="_blank">Human Resources</a>, Los Angeles, February 18, 2017</p>

<p>1. Geneva Skeen – Pop Song 16:48<br />
2. Sarah Rara – Separating the Air 20:12 – <a href="http://touchradio.org.uk/she">Projected Text</a></p>

<p>For the closing of Yann Novak’s exhibition <a href="http://www.yannnovak.com/exhibitions/repose/" target="_blank"><em>Repose</em></a>, Novak invited Geneva Skeen and Sarah Rara to perform inside/alongside his installation. Each artist's performance was accompanied by the sound of Novak’s installation demonstrated here via a room-recording from the event.</p>

<p>Skeen’s <em>Pop Song</em> is a temporal response to Novak’s drone work, and a cultural response to our times. In harmonizing with Novak’s loop – divided into 3-4 minute segments (the average acceptable length of a pop song) – Skeen’s <em>Pop Song</em> acknowledges that populist times call for populist measures, but refuses populist comfort, acceptance, and pale standards of beauty as means of resistance.</p>

<p>Rara’s <em>Separating the Air</em>: games of listening and learning between voice and computer at the boundary between music and speech. Each part is a device to punctuate silence, divide time, move the air.</p>

<p>Photo: Christopher Wormald</p>

<p>Subscribe to the TouchPod podcast of TouchRadio via the <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=80842701">iTunes Music Store</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.touchshop.org/touchradio/Radio128.mp3">Play "Live in Los Angeles"</a></p>

<p><a href="https://soundcloud.com/geneeeeves" target="_blank">soundcloud.com/geneeeeves</a><br />
<a href="http://www.sarahrara.com" target="_blank">www.sarahrara.com</a><br />
<a href="http://www.touchradio.org.uk" target="_blank">www.touchradio.org.uk</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_128_geneva_skeen_s.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_radio_128_geneva_skeen_s.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March 24, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch is 35 Today</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Today, 11th March, is the official 35th anniversary of the founding of Touch in 1982...<br />
<span class="smallpic"><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/245x/soulkitchen.jpg" /></span><br />
First contact with New Order after their concert at the Newcastle Mayfair on 11th March 1982…</p>

<p><a href="http://touch33.net/full-catalogue-by-date">You can follow our progress year by year here...</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_is_35_today.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_is_35_today.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on March 11, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 57 | UnicaZurn - “Transpandorem”</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Vinyl LP and download - 2 tracks</p>

<p>Release date: 27th January 2017</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE57.jpg" alt="Transpandorem" /></p>

<p>Written, recorded and produced by David Knight &amp; Stephen Thrower<br />
Additional production assistance: Ivan Pavlov<br />
Cut by Jason @ Transition<br />
Artwork &amp; Photography: Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p><a href="http://internationaltimes.it/on-the-translation-of-spirit-to-snake/">The International Times Review can be read here</a></p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Breathe the Snake<br />
2. Pale Salt Seam</p>

<p>UnicaZürn (David Knight and Stephen Thrower).</p>

<p>UnicaZürn build their long, ceaselessly evolving musical compositions through a process of improvisation followed by careful editing and processing. Their music, drawn from subconscious associations while recording, is frequently aquatic or oceanic in overall mood and texture. Knight has spent most of his life living on the banks of the Thames while Thrower resides on the East Sussex coast, and their musical flights of imagination tend toward rolling river dynamics and the open seas of synthesised sound.</p>

<p>For UnicaZürn, tidal imagery, oceanic forms and the slow rhythms of coastal water are a recurring structural presence, with strong associations of rootlessness, of being far away from home, a stranger in a strange land. The inability of human lungs to breathe water endows rivers and seas with a special poetics: a boundary between two different but inter-related states. On the one hand, solidity, clarity, definition; on the other, fluidity, uncertainty, dissolution. The sense of a threshold between opposites gives rise to an elusive otherness, suggesting a portal through which the everyday world can be escaped. Death under the water, the survivors of a lost kingdom clinging to the rocks of an unfamiliar island, a coastal boat ride into deepest abstraction, a deserted beach expressing a world outside reality.</p>

<p>A sexual frisson too: a hovering at the brink, poised at the turbulent edge of pleasure, swept away into oblivion. Do we head toward the sea when we want to escape? And at the coastline, do we walk to the edge because we want to jump, or be swept away by an unexpected wave? There’s a darkness in the sea, even if illuminated by the most dazzling sunshine. Open horizons shows the clutter of our lives to be transient, and as we look to the sea we feel a dizzying sense of the eternal. Aquatic sensibility, oceanic timescales: the action of the salt sea beating on the shore. Each grain of sand a rock smashed to dust. Beaches are cosmic, elemental. They are images of time.</p>

<p>UnicaZürn’s core instrumentation blends analogue synthesiser, mellotron and electric piano with electric guitar and clarinet. Both Thrower and Knight draw upon their love and wide experience of of electronic music, from the outer shores of Stockhausen to the outer spaceways of Tangerine Dream. In addition, Knight is reknowned for his pioneering multi-textured fretwork with Danielle Dax and his ambient guitar settings for Lydia Lunch, while Thrower’s reed playing provided a distinctive melancholy in Coil and emerged as electro-acoustic texture in Cyclobe.</p>

<p>The title “Pale Salt Seam” is drawn from the poem "Night-Song of the Andalusian Sailors" by Federico García Lorca. Parts of “Pale Salt Seam” were recorded live at the Ironmongers Row Baths on 2nd March 2013.</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?products_id=XXX">Pre-order Unica Zürn - "Transpandorem" [Vinyl LP] in the TouchShop</a><br />
<a href="http://www.unicazurn.com">www.unicazurn.com</a></p>

<p><a href="http://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/UZthewire.png">You can read a review in The Wire here</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_57_unicazurn_transpandore_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_57_unicazurn_transpandore_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 13, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>UnicaZürn Live at Cafe Oto | 5th January 2017</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Stephen Thrower and David Knight performed at Café Oto as UnicaZürn on Wednesday 25th January 2017. Their debut album for Touch, Transpandorem (Touch # Tone 57), was released the same week...</p>

<p>You can read a review here <a href="http://internationaltimes.it/the-pandorem-a-place-for-the-soul/" target="_blank">in The International Times</a></p>

<p>Touch presents...<br />
Live at Café Oto</p>

<p>UnicaZürn’s performance at Café OTO saw the core duo of DAVID KNIGHT &amp; STEPHEN THROWER joined by DANIELLE DAX (vocals) and DAVID J. SMITH (percussion).</p>

<p>DANIELLE DAX – singer, songwriter, multi-instrumentalist and mixed-media artist – sang ‘Jack Sorrow’ on the first UnicaZürn LP, ‘Temporal Bends’. Her artworks are featured on the covers of the first UnicaZürn CD, ‘Temporal Bends’ and their recent cassette-only release for the Tapeworm label, ‘Omegapavilion’. This performance will mark her return to live vocals after a decade’s absence.</p>

<p>DAVID J. SMITH is a founder member of the progressive art-rock groups GUAPO and STARGARZER’S ASSISTANT (the latter also featuring David Knight), and percussionist with Stephen Thrower’s group CYCLOBE.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.unicazurn.com">UnicaZürn</a><br />
with <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/search/charles%20bullen">Charles Bullen</a></p>

<p><em>“...like Jacques Cousteau meets HP Lovecraft twenty thousand leagues under the sea.”</em> – FREQ Magazine</p>

<p><a href="http://freq.org.uk/reviews/unicazurn-charles-bullen-live-at-cafe-oto/">and a review here</a></p>

<p><strong>UnicaZürn</strong> emerged in 2009 from the belly of a live-improv' beast called The Amal Gamal Ensemble. David Knight and Stephen Thrower have worked with the Ensemble since its inception in 2001. UnicaZürn music also has its roots in free improvisation, but the results are then burnished and restructured with intensive studio sculpting.</p>

<p><em>“Knight and Thrower bring a deep intuition to the performances, allowing treated guitar, saxophone and clarinet to blend with analogue synthesizers, mellotron and organ… Only occasionally does a locked snippet of sound repeat itself enough to suggest anything like an insistent beat”</em> – Ken Hollings, The Wire</p>

<p><strong>Charles Bullen</strong> was a member of timeless pre/post-everything trio This Heat. He grew up in Liverpool and after moving to London in the early 70’s he formed the improvising duo Dolphin Logic with Charles Hayward, which later, with the addition of “non-musician” Gareth Williams, became This Heat. After releasing two seminal albums the band split in 1982 and Bullen made an album the following year under the name Lifetones focusing on repetition and a more syncopated dub influenced sound. Earlier this year, after a series of re-issues on Light In The Attic Records, Bullen and Hayward formed This Is Not This Heat, a group assembled to realise and re-imagine the music of This Heat with several musical luminaries from the London experimental music world including Daniel O’Sullivan, Alex Ward, James Sedwards, Alexis Taylor, Frank Byng, John Edwards and Oren Marshall.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE57.jpg" alt="Transpandorem" /></p>

<p><strong>Transpandorem</strong></p>

<p>Vinyl LP and download - 2 tracks<br />
Release date: 27th January 2017</p>

<p>Written, recorded and produced by David Knight &amp; Stephen Thrower<br />
Additional production assistance: Ivan Pavlov<br />
Cut by Jason @ Transition<br />
Artwork &amp; Photography: Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p>Track listing:</p>

<p>1. Breathe the Snake<br />
2. Pale Salt Seam</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/unicazurn_live_at_cafe_oto_5th.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/unicazurn_live_at_cafe_oto_5th.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 13, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Touch Quadraphonic @ The Ace Hotel | 14th January 2017</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Desert X and VOLUME present an evening of collaborative soundscapes at Ace Hotel<br />
&amp; Swim Club.</p>

<p>STARTS AT 6:00pm</p>

<p>The event will present a quadrophonic sound installation of work by Jana Windren, Chris Watson, Philip Jeck, BJNilsen, Mark Van Hoen, Yann Novak, Achim Mohné and Claire M Singer. The event will will also feature performances by Geneva Skeen and Bethan Kellough that will begin at 7:30pm.</p>

<p>FREE</p>

<p>Ace Hotel &amp; Swim Club<br />
701 E. Palm Canyon Dr.<br />
Palm Springs, CA 92264</p>

<p><a href="https://www.acehotel.com/calendar/palmsprings/desert-x-presents-evening-collaborative-soundscapes?mc_cid=26ba8b1299&amp;mc_eid=e416c8cd14">www.acehotel.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touch_quadraphonic_the_ace_hot.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touch_quadraphonic_the_ace_hot.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 13, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Lend Me Your Ears | 2016 Roundup</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>This year's list has been unusually challenging since a number of key labels were in overdrive. Grand projects have multiplied too. So our self-constraining methodology became even more masochistic.</p>

<p>How, to take an especially painful example, to choose between Bethan Kellough's Aven &amp; Claire M. Singer's Solas? Two exceptional releases that each expanded notions of sound palettes &amp; what could be done with them, but both on Touch (about whom more shortly...).</p>

<p>&amp; that's to exclude Yann Novak's Ornamentation, Simon Scott's Floodlines, Anna von Hauswolff's Kallan (Prototype) &amp; Fennesz's Mahler Remix, despite all four clearly demanding recognitition as part of the year's 'best'.</p>

<p><a href="http://earslend.blogspot.co.uk/2016/12/capelli-camicia.html">earslend.blogspot.co.uk/2016/12/capelli-camicia.html</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/lend_me_your_ears_2016_roundup.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/lend_me_your_ears_2016_roundup.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on February 13, 2017</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>TOUCHLINE 9 | Ipek Gorgun – “Aphelion”</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://touch33.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/27/TouchLine9.jpg" alt="touchline9" width="585" height="393" /></p>

<p>Digital Download - 8 audio tracks – 48' 23" + mpg + pdf (1.2Gb)<br />
The link to the .zip can be found in your email receipt [also in your account history]</p>

<p>1. Kairos 5:28<br />
2. Fata Morgana 4:42<br />
3. Bloodbenchers 8:54<br />
4. Lethe 2:54<br />
5. Martyrs 8:22<br />
6. Dendrite 4:20<br />
7. Nightingale 9:20<br />
8. Troubling Speech 3:50 [bonus track]</p>

<p>Kairos video: Noetic Works<br />
PDF photo book: Ipek Gorgun<br />
Recording and Mixing: Ipek Gorgun<br />
Mastering: Barkin Engin</p>

<p>"The dictionary describes <em>aphelion</em> as “the point in the path of a celestial body (as a planet) that is farthest from the sun”, which i reckon is a suitable title since it reminded me of the night time, when I recorded and edited the majority of this work.</p>

<p>The night makes me think about openness and gathering. To me, it is a state of togetherness in which things are allowed to keep their own identity, yet they are covered under the veil of darkness. From time to time we may recognise such things as they are, but the night also evokes the so- called luxury of intuition, helping us become aware of their existence without using our sense of sight.</p>

<p>One might feel that the night has a disturbing, chaotic and uncontrollable character. I can relate to that since it becomes harder to see; our ocularcentric modern ways of living are being challenged. Contrary to the sunlight that helps us divide, analyze and govern, the night tends to reveal our most primitive selves, as well as uncovering our deepest thoughts, untold dreams and memories. In addition, in such state of openness, the lack of light provides more space for the activation of other senses.</p>

<p>This is when hearing becomes so acute - as well as touching and smelling. I still think about smell, but hearing can also be associated with touch, since we are literally touched by sound in the form of waves through space, and they become audible in the range between 20Hz. and 20kHz. The night makes this contact even more obvious.</p>

<p>Such communication is the most intimate that two complete strangers (who will probably not meet again) can be. And I'm once again grateful for my own personal aphelion (2:44 AM, GMT+2) at the moment for helping me write this to you, beloved listener."</p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?products_id=800">Buy &amp; download Ipek Gorgun - "Aphelion" [.wav + pdf] in the TouchShop</a> - The link to the .zip can be found in your email receipt [also in your account history]<br />
<a href="http://www.touch33.net/touchline">You can read more about TOUCHLINE here</a></p>

<p><!--more--></p>

<p>Born and raised in Ankara - Turkey, Ipek Gorgun is an electronic music composer currently enrolled in the doctoral program of Sonic Arts at Istanbul Technical University's Center for Advanced Studies in Music.</p>

<p>After graduating from Bilkent University with a degree in Political Science, she completed her master's studies in Philosophy at Galatasaray University with her dissertation in entitled “le Silence de l’Etre-avec et de l’Etre-Seul dans Etre et Temps de Heidegger” (The Silence of Being-Alone and Being-Together in Heidegger’s Being and Time).</p>

<p>As one of the participants of the Red Bull Music Academy in 2014, she performed in Tokyo as an opening artist for Ryoji Ikeda’s “Test Pattern No: 6” and joined Otomo Yoshidide for a collective improvisation project. In April 2015, she was invited to Cologne as artist-in-residence and performer by the New Music Foundation of Cologne (ON: Cologne) and Opekta Ateliers.</p>

<p>After a brief education in classical guitar, her journey as a performer began in 2001 as a fill-in drummer for Four Handle One Scandal, a punk-rock/ska band. After switching to bass guitar and singing, she took place in experimental music projects such as Bedroomdrunk, Coquelicot and Vector Hugo between the years 2001 – 2012 and opened for Jennifer Finch from L7 and Simon Scott from Slowdive, while playing live with David Brown from Brazzaville in Istanbul and Ankara. She has released two EPs with Bedroomdrunk, entitled “This is What Happened (2003)” and “Raw (2007)”.</p>

<p>Besides group projects and solo performances, she also composed the soundtrack for the documentary ‘Yok Anasinin Soyadi (Mrs. His Name) directed by Hande Cayir in 2012, portraying Turkish women’s struggle for keeping their original surnames after marriage.</p>

<p>In addition to musical efforts, Ipek Gorgun practices performance, street and abstract photography. She won the IPA honorable mention award in 2013-14 with her work entitled "Bubblegun Daydreamer" and in 2013, she worked as the advertisement photographer for Contemporary Istanbul Art Fair. She has also contibuted to contemporary poetry journals such as Yumusakge and Tenedos between 2007 – 2009.</p>

<p>Reviews for the self-released version:</p>

<p>“Splintered bleeps phase in and out across funnelling drones make for a delicate introduction, but they’ve very soon obliterated, bulldozed buy a barelling blast of deep, droning, high-volume electronic noise and scraping feedback, fuzzed out at the edges with distortion. On Aphelion, Gorgun exploits the full dynamic range, moving between soft and sometimes ominous quieter passages to louder, harsher tones; sometimes gliding, long notes hover, while at others, sharp, sudden arrive unexpectedly to jolt the listener. In terms of frequencies, too, Gorgun explores the sonic spectrum to powerful and sometimes uncomfortable effect.” [Christopher Nosnibor, Aural Aggravation]</p>

<p>“‘Glacial’ is a term often used to describe experimental electronic music but that would be a criminally wasteful term of expression to describe the shifting, pulsing and often gnarled soundscapes of Ipek Gorgun. At times it does indeed have a pinpoint crystal iciness about it with what feels like washes of cold, pure Eno or Fennesz like sound invading the head space, and yet at other times the growling, bubbling analogue synths of someone like Aphex Twin spring to mind, or the odd ball, twitchy, cult composers like François Bayle or Eliane Radigue. Whichever way you look at it, this is a fine example of intricate electronic sound design.” [Vision Music Promotion, London]</p>

<p>“What makes Aphelion extra special is that even though that build is gradual and patient, it never feels like an exercise or a closed system. Each track progresses with an unencumbered air; Gorgun has figured out how to make careful, deliberate steps feel like spontaneous leaps, and vice versa. So when Aphelion is droning, it feels ready to burst into pointillist clusters; when it’s busy, it feels on the verge of calm. By the end it actually is calm, drifting into a beatific denouement that’s fully earned by the diverse activity that preceded it. But this is music too rich and complex for easy endings, and all the conclusion really does is make me want to press play again.” [Marc Masters, 200 Words Pitchfork/The Out Door]</p>

<p>“Listened to in a state of semi-willing wakefulness in the imminent expectation of the arrival of hypnotised, tired-out dozing that movement through a landscape can engender, Aphelion matches those moods and the state of hovering just between consciousness and collapse. shifts and half-cogent tones seem to speak of a dormant world of figurative symbolism and archetypal tone poems celebrating the restful dissolve into the slumbering arms of an electronic Morpheus.” [Antron S. Meister, FreqZine]</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touchline_9_ipek_gorgun_apheli.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touchline_9_ipek_gorgun_apheli.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on December 14, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>UnicaZürn</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Stephen Thrower and David Knight will perform at Café Oto as Unica Zürn on Wednesday 25th January 2017. Their debut album for Touch, Transpandorem (Touch # Tone 57), is due to be released on the same day...</p>

<p><a href="https://www.cafeoto.co.uk/events/touch-presents-unicazurn/">Book tickets for Café Oto</a></p>

<p>Touch presents...<br />
Live at Café Oto</p>

<p><a href="http://www.unicazurn.com">Unica Zürn</a><br />
with <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/search/charles%20bullen">Charles Bullen</a></p>

<p><em>“...like Jacques Cousteau meets HP Lovecraft twenty thousand leagues under the sea.”</em> – FREQ Magazine</p>

<p><strong>UnicaZürn</strong> emerged in 2009 from the belly of a live-improv' beast called The Amal Gamal Ensemble. David Knight and Stephen Thrower have worked with the Ensemble since its inception in 2001. UnicaZürn music also has its roots in free improvisation, but the results are then burnished and restructured with intensive studio sculpting.</p>

<p><em>“Knight and Thrower bring a deep intuition to the performances, allowing treated guitar, saxophone and clarinet to blend with analogue synthesizers, mellotron and organ… Only occasionally does a locked snippet of sound repeat itself enough to suggest anything like an insistent beat”</em> – Ken Hollings, The Wire</p>

<p><strong>Charles Bullen</strong> was a member of timeless pre/post-everything trio This Heat. He grew up in Liverpool and after moving to London in the early 70’s he formed the improvising duo Dolphin Logic with Charles Hayward, which later, with the addition of “non-musician” Gareth Williams, became This Heat. After releasing two seminal albums the band split in 1982 and Bullen made an album the following year under the name Lifetones focusing on repetition and a more syncopated dub influenced sound. Earlier this year, after a series of re-issues on Light In The Attic Records, Bullen and Hayward formed This Is Not This Heat, a group assembled to realise and re-imagine the music of This Heat with several musical luminaries from the London experimental music world including Daniel O’Sullivan, Alex Ward, James Sedwards, Alexis Taylor, Frank Byng, John Edwards and Oren Marshall.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/unicazurn.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/unicazurn.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on December  1, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>TOUCHLINE 8 | Gravitas - &quot;a frequency crescendo in 11 movements&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Download only - 1 track - 27' 34"</p>

<p>Photography by Heitor Alvelos, design by Jon Wozencroft<br />
Release date: 21st October 2016</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TouchLine8.jpg"></p>

<p>Track listing and notes:</p>

<p>1. a frequency crescendo in 11 movements 27' 34"</p>

<p>Heitor Alvelos, digital frequencies<br />
Anselmo Canha, bass, field recordings<br />
Anabela Duarte, treated voice<br />
José Maria Lopes, guitar<br />
Jaime Munárriz, guitar, trumpet, electronics<br />
Jono Podmore, theremin<br />
André Rocha, arduino-activated lemon tree (concert)</p>

<p>"Gravitas" is a studio re-construction and re-consideration of a sound performance that took place at the futureplaces medialab on October 24, 2015, in Porto, Portugal. </p>

<p>Woven and edited by Heitor Alvelos, Oporto, August - September 2016<br />
Mastered by Jono Podmore, Köln, September 2016</p>

<p>The words that bookend the piece belong to Bernadette Martou (1962-2015)</p>

<p>The original plan was to release the gig itself, but a series of technical and aesthetic drawbacks, affecting both the performance and the recording, rendered this undesirable. The state of exhaustion of some of the participants, after a four-day marathon running multiple fronts of the medialab, certainly did not help: yet all reasons boil down to a simple evidence - every performer has at some point found him/herself in a situation where all the ideal ingredients seem to be there, and yet the momentum just does not follow. This was one such evening. It happens.</p>

<p>However, the ingredients remained very much present, and so did the commitment of all involved. A decision was thus made to pay justice to what had not been.</p>

<p>The process towards "Gravitas" rebuilt, the present piece, began with each contributor revisiting their own sounds through their own means, while being allowed to change them further, if desired. One rule applied onstage, and that one rule remained: each individual contribution should be a crescendo from infra-sound to ultra-sound (voice mercifully exempted from this rule). During this second process, individual tracks were not shared with others until finished by each contributor.</p>

<p>The source material was abundant and opened up a wealth of possibilities, as it would; so in good paradoxical fashion, the choice was made to be sparse and surgical in its use, and open up as much of a reflective and introspective mood as possible. The concert recording is also in there, minimally, whenever it made sense for it to be. Other variations of "Gravitas" may surface, as there is substance in much of what was left out; for the time being, however, this is the gig that could have been.</p>

<p>Why "Gravitas"?</p>

<p>Every year since 2008, futureplaces gathers media creatives, thinkers and researchers in an attempt to see and act further beyond the immediate digital allure: firstly by acknowledging that so much of today's technology has yet to deliver on its promise of personal, social and cultural emancipation, and then by picking up from this evidence in various hands-on fronts. Futureplaces has been a purposefully chaotic meeting point where media research meets citizenship, in contextual, tangible projects that rehearse unorthodox uses for new media. Viral epiphanies, one could say.</p>

<p>This mission, at the core of futureplaces since its inception, observes and interprets current trends and developments. Every year a motto is proposed, an answer to the zeitgeist. Gravitas is, we believe, an antidote to the hallucinatory abandonment and volatility of the present times; a call for wisdom, for grounding and sobriety. And as with a wider set of choice words that seem to have vanished from our vocabulary, it is a largely absent term whose meaning - whose role in our consciousness - has paradoxically never seemed so decisive.</p>

<p>Through gravitas we emerge and soar: thus the journey from infra-sound to ultra-sound. From rootedness to elevation.</p>

<p></p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?products_id=797">Buy & download Gravitas - "a frequency crescendo in 11 movements" [.wav + pdf] in the TouchShop</a> - The link to the .zip can be found in your email receipt [also in your account history]<br />
<a href="http://www.touch33.net/touchline">You can read more about TOUCHLINE here</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/touchline_8_gravitas.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/touchline_8_gravitas.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on October 20, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Tone 55 | Yann Novak &quot;Ornamentation&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Compact disc in wallet - 1 track - 49;00</p>

<p>Artwork & photography by Jon Wozencroft<br />
Release date: 11th November 2016</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TONE55.jpg"></p>

<p>Track listing and notes:</p>

<p>1. Ornamentation</p>

<p>Presented live in Los Angeles. Source material includes field recordings captured throughout the United States and Canada from 2006–2016 and modular synthesizer recordings, all digitally altered.</p>

<p>Yann Novak is a multidisciplinary artist based in Los Angeles. Ornamentation is Novak's first physical release on Touch and continues his investigations of presence, stillness and mindfulness through the construction of immersive spaces, both literal and figurative. On Ornamentation Novak resists modernism's problematic relationship to race, class and labour, and attempts to decouple contemporary minimalist sound work from this historical precedent. The title refers to Adolf Loos's notorious 1913 manifesto, 'Ornament and Crime,' in which the author argues that the desire to adorn architecture, the body, objects, etc., is a primitive impulse, and the proper and moral evolution of Western culture depends in part upon the removal of ornamentation from daily life. Loos devalued the labor traditionally associated with aesthetics and beauty, and equated ornamentation with the degenerate. In this context, one could consider ornamentation as a way of viewing decay. His examples as such (tattoos, fashion, style, painting, et al.) predictably fell along divisions of race and class, coding modernity as the next outward manifestation of white, capitalist patriarchy. Throughout the process of creating Ornamentation, Novak attempts to sidestep some of Loos's modernist intolerances by focusing on the labor of composition itself, rather than particular processes or structures. Novak began by incorporating specific field recordings from his archive, deliberately selected for their poor quality; awkward interruptions, low fidelity smartphone recordings, problematic frequencies. The selection of these difficult sounds, processed alongside recordings of his modular synthesizer, created a unique set of challenges for Novak where the familiar, reductive approaches would fail to be useful and ultimately abandoned in favor of more dynamic, additive, and laborious process. Unlike minimalism with its roots in modernism, or "sound art" with its conceptual biases, Novak creates a work that acknowledges these conventions, yet stands apart as a meditation on beauty, labour, and aesthetics; Ornamentation as an adornment of time itself.</p>

<p>You can read an interview in <a href="http://www.attnmagazine.co.uk/features/10856">ATTN:Magazine here</a></p>

<p></p>

<p><a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?products_id=793">Order Yann Novak's “Ornamentation” [CD + 24bit DL] in the TouchShop</a><br />
<a href="http://www.yannnovak.com">www.yannnovak.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/tone_55_yann_novak_ornamentati_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/tone_55_yann_novak_ornamentati_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on October 13, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Spire live on NTS Radio | 7th October 2016</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mscharding.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/10/organ-reframed-art1.jpg" alt="organ-reframed-art1" width="585" height="585" /></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/spire_live_on_nts_radio_7th_oc.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/spire_live_on_nts_radio_7th_oc.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on October  5, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>TO:102 | Lustmord &quot;Dark Matter&quot;</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Compact disc in digifile - 3 tracks - 70:38</p>

<p>Artwork & photography by Jon Wozencroft<br />
Release date: 30th September 2016</p>

<p><img src="https://www.touch33.net/images/585x/TO102.jpg"></p>

<p>Track listing and notes:</p>

<p>1. Subspace<br />
2. Astronomicom<br />
3. Black Static</p>

<p>Conceived and Produced by B.Lustmord<br />
Recorded in Los Angeles October-December 2015<br />
Artwork & Photography by Jon Wozencroft</p>

<p>Derived from an audio library of cosmological activity collected between 1993 and 2003. It was gathered from various sources including NASA (Cape Canaveral, Ames, The Jet Propulsion Laboratory and Arecibo), The Very Large Array, The National Radio Astronomy Observatory and various educational institutions and private contributors throughout the USA</p>

<p>Lustmord writes: "The Universe we inhabit is a vast expanse far larger than we are able to comprehend. As we attempt to understand its underlying structure and as we gain new insight into the nature of matter, new questions arise and further gaps in our understanding are revealed.</p>

<p>Behind the world that we experience lies a veil of darkness and much is hidden between, beyond and unseen. </p>

<p>We are limited by our inability to truly grasp the infinite breadth of the Universe, the time scales involved in its measure and our insignificant position within.</p>

<p>Some things will always be unknowable, and existence does not begin or end with man's conception.</p>

<p>Everything that has ever been observed by man, even with our most sophisticated instruments, amounts to less than five percent of the Universe.</p>

<p>Approximately sixty-eight percent of the Universe is unseen dark energy and approximately twenty-seven percent is unseen dark matter. We have yet to discover what dark matter is, and only know the things it is not. Although it has not been directly observed, its existence and properties are inferred from its effects on visible matter, its influence on the Universe's large-scale structure, and its effects in the cosmic microwave background. </p>

<p>The universe began of darkness, not of light.</p>

<p>While space is a virtual vacuum, it does not mean there is no sound in space. It exists in space as naturally occurring electromagnetic vibrations, many well within the range of human hearing while others exist at different regions of the electromagnetic spectrum and these can be adjusted with software to bring them within our audio range.</p>

<p>The recordings of these interactions in space come from several different environments including radio, ultra violet, microwave and X-ray data and within these spectra a wide range of sources including interstellar plasma and molecules, radio galaxies, pulsars masers and quasars, charged particle interactions and emissions, radiation, exotic astrophysical objects, cosmic jets and flares from magnetars."</p>

<p>About Lustmord:</p>

<p>Widely credited as the originator of the “Dark Ambient” genre. Credits on over forty motion pictures including The Crow and Underworld. One of the two composers for the Turtle Rock/2K game Evolve. Worked with John Balance, Chris & Cosey, Clock DVA, Current 93, Paul Haslinger, Maynard James Keenan, Melvins, Nurse With Wound, Tool and Wes Borland amongst others. </p>

<p><br />
<a href="http://touchshop.org/product_info.php?products_id=787">Pre-order Lustmord's “Dark Matter” [CD] in the TouchShop</a><br />
<a href="http://www.lustmord.com">www.lustmord.com</a></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/news/to102_lustmord_dark_matter.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/news/to102_lustmord_dark_matter.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">news</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Posted on September  1, 2016</pubDate>
      </item>
      
   </channel>
</rss>