<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Touch Recipe Book</title>
      <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/</link>
      <description>Artists and others offer their favourite recipes to mark the 25th anniversary of Touch</description>
      <language>en</language>
      <copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 19:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/</generator>
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs> 

            <item>
         <title>Renato Balsadonna</title>
         <excerpt>Pasta con Gamberi </excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients for 4 people:</p>

<p>Garlic x3 cloves.<br />
Olive oil.<br />
Fillet of Anchovies x5.<br />
Pepperoncino. <br />
Fresh cherry tomatoes 14/16, chopped.<br />
Fresh flat leaf parsley, a very good handful.<br />
Fresh prawns (unshelled) 200g.<br />
Dry White wine for cooking, 1 glass.<br />
Salt & pepper.</p>

<p>100g pasta per person preferably <br />
Linguine, De Cecco.</p>

<p><br />
Method.</p>

<p>Take a large deep pan for the pasta and fill it with water, add a small handful of rock salt if you have some. Bring to the boil and add the pasta. Cook the pasta for the exact time it says in the pack. Normally about 11/12 mins.  </p>

<p>Meanwhile take a large sauté pan and poor in olive oil, enough to make a film of oil on the bottom of the pan. With the back of a wooden spoon press the pealed garlic cloves into the oil (I find this easier to do in the pan before I put the oil in otherwise it's slips and slides!) until lightly browned, take care not to burn the oil or the garlic. When lightly browned take out the garlic take off the heat and add the anchovies and break up so they almost dissolve into the oil. It might spit a bit when adding anchovies so take care. </p>

<p>Put pan back on the heat and add the prawns and the White wine and stir, let the wine evaporate (the heat should be quite high for this). <br />
Add the chopped cherry tomatoes and stir allow them to boil in order to make a little sauce. <br />
Add a pinch of pepperoncino, enough to add a little flavour and depending on how hot you want it. <br />
Add salt & pepper. </p>

<p>When pasta is ready remove immediately from the heat drain pasta in a colander, tip pasta onto prawn mixture and mix together. Stir in the fresh parsley leaves and serve immediately. </p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/renato_balsadonna.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/renato_balsadonna.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Pasta</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 15:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Harri Sjostrom</title>
         <excerpt>Extended Pesto al Harri</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>You will need:</p>

<p>100g of your favourite pesto verde<br />
30g panna (cream)<br />
30g crème fraîche<br />
100g ewe's cheese<br />
olive oil<br />
a handful of walnuts<br />
fresh garlic<br />
500g spaghetti</p>

<p>10 minutes</p>

<p><br />
Let the pasta slip into boiling water.<br />
Bruise the fresh garlic and walnuts with a good shot of olive oil.<br />
Add ewe's cheese, crème fraîche, panna, mash everything well with a fork. Add the pesto, go on mashing until all is fluffy. </p>

<p>Add two spoons of the extended pesto for one serving of spaghetti and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3bLGzJnPFk">watch this</a> while you <br />
enjoy.</p>

<p>Goes well with a classic caprese (sliced tomatos, mozarella, rucola, olive oil, balsamico, sea salt and ground pepper). You can keep the pesto in the fridge for two days in a jar when covered with olive oil.</p>

<p><br />
<img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/stephan_mathieu_2.jpg"></p>

<p><em>[submitted by Stephan Mathieu]</em></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/harri_sjostrom.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/harri_sjostrom.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Pasta</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 09:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Stephan Mathieu</title>
         <excerpt>Sugo Nepalese Bolognese</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>800g ground beef + 200g ground jerky</p>

<p>roast gently until medium, add 1 bottle of nice red italian, until the ground meat is just covered. Let it simmer softly for at least 2hrs while slowly adding the rest of <br />
the vino to keep everything covered.</p>

<p>Add</p>

<p>600g peeled and mashed tomatos plus grated ginger, ground cumin, cardamon, coriander, seasalt and black pepper for seasoning half way through and a proper dash of pasta water just before serving.</p>

<p>Add some fresh peppermint leaves and enjoy with Fusilli.</p>

<p><br />
<img src="stephan_mathieu_1.jpg"></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/stephan_mathieu_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/stephan_mathieu_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Pasta</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 11:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Jon Wozencroft</title>
         <excerpt>Emergency Pasta</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/pan.jpg"></p>

<p>When you’ve forgotten to get the shopping in, for those times when you are just too busy to think… You can’t afford a restaurant meal, you can’t afford the time…</p>

<p>This’ll take 15 minutes from start to finish.</p>

<p>Ingredients – the things you should always have in your kitchen for such an eventuality:</p>

<p>1 tin chopped/plum tomatoes<br />
3-5 cloves fresh garlic (depending on size)<br />
liberal amounts of pepper, a generous pinch of salt<br />
extra virgin olive oil <br />
any herbs you have to hand – oregano, basil, thyme (optional) <br />
parmesan cheese (always have some of this – I tend to forget sometimes)</p>

<p>Heat olive oil in a large pan, add finely chopped garlic, seal at high heat for 5-10 seconds, add tomatoes, bring to a simmer before adding pepper, salt. </p>

<p>Multiply amounts accordingly – one tin of tomatoes generally good for 2 people.</p>

<p>Having boiled large saucepan of (slightly salted) water in the meantime, add spoonful of olive oil before immersing pasta of choice. Spaghetti never disappoints.</p>

<p>By now the tomato sauce is well on the boil. Turn it right down and let the excess liquid evaporate. Simmer on a low heat.</p>

<p>Tip – warm the plates if you can, pasta cools very quickly and this’ll be cold before you’ve finished it if you don’t.</p>

<p>The pack of spaghetti will tell you to boil it for 8-10 minutes. At 7mins 30 you have to start checking its “al dente” status, and turn off when it’s how you like it. For me it’s 8 mins 20 – anything over 9 minutes gets mushy!</p>

<p>Serve, sprinkle liberal amounts of parmesan and more pepper.</p>

<p>Delicious. Total cost less than a pound.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/plate.jpg"></p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/jon_wozencroft.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/jon_wozencroft.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Pasta</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 08:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Stephan Mathieu</title>
         <excerpt>Linguine with Tuna Sugo</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.touch33.net/recipebook/images/tunapornshot.jpg"></p>

<p>300g white tuna (natural/no oil or spice, dolphin friendly)</p>

<p>100g bacon (chopped in cubes)</p>

<p>500g cream (Panna)</p>

<p>a handful of salted capers (potted)</p>

<p>a handful of black olives</p>

<p>nutmeg</p>

<p>black pepper corns</p>

<p>sea salt</p>

<p>500g Linguine</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>Fry bacon in a pan, reduce heat and add the tuna, capers, grated nutmeg, crushed pepper and a proper pinch of crushed sea salt, let everything simmer smoothly for 2 minutes without letting the condiments become dry. Stir constantly.</p>

<p>Now add the cream and olives, churn, heat up for some seconds and keep everything simmering very smoothly with closed lid for 8-10 minutes (while the Linguine get boiled). Stir now and then, add some more pepper, the sugo should be nice and fluffy now and ready to meet the pasta!</p>

<p>Goes well with rucola and a balsamico, olive oil + mustard dressing.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/stephan_mathieu.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/pasta/stephan_mathieu.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Pasta</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
      
   </channel>
</rss>