<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Touch Recipe Book</title>
      <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/</link>
      <description>Artists and others offer their favourite recipes to mark the 25th anniversary of Touch</description>
      <language>en</language>
      <copyright>Copyright 2016</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 19:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <generator>http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/</generator>
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs> 

            <item>
         <title>Bjorn Ekstrom</title>
         <excerpt>Potato and leek soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>5-6 potatoes<br />
1 leek<br />
2 big yellow onions<br />
1 cube of vegetable boullion<br />
2 dl or 7 oz of cream<br />
salt<br />
white pepper<br />
olive oil<br />
7 dl or 24 oz of water<br />
 <br />
Peel and chop the potato and the onion.</p>

<p>Fry the potato and the onion in a pot with oil.</p>

<p>Split and rinse the leek. Chop it into small pieces.</p>

<p>Fry the leek together with the potato and the onion.</p>

<p>Pour water into the pot, add the boullion and let it boil.</p>

<p>When the soup is boiling, pour the cream into the pot and let the soup cook until the potato gets soft.</p>

<p>Add salt and pepper.</p>

<p>Serve with brown bread and milk.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/bjorn_ekstrom.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/bjorn_ekstrom.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 18:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Boris Karloff</title>
         <excerpt>Guacamole Boris Karloff</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>2 avocados<br />
1 med. tomato, chopped fine<br />
1 small onion minced<br />
1 tbsp. chopped canned green chilles<br />
1 tbsp. lemon juice<br />
2 tsp. sherry<br />
Dash cayenne, optional<br />
Salt, pepper</p>

<p>Peel and mash avocados. Add tomato, chilles, then stir in lemon juice, sherry and seasonings to taste, blending well.</p>

<p>Serve as a dip for tortilla pieces or corn chips or as a canapé spread. Makes 10 to 12 appetizer servings.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/boris_karloff.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/boris_karloff.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 10:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Eddie Nuttall</title>
         <excerpt>Cider and Red Onion Soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients (Serves 2):</p>

<p>1 x Red Onion<br />
1 x Vegetable Stock Cube<br />
2 x Cans of Cider (doesn’t have to be fancy (Strongbow, Magners, etc.). However, do not use White Ace or White Lightning or similar, this is not a good thing to put into your body under any circumstances)<br />
Salt/sugar/mixed herbs to taste<br />
Olive Oil</p>

<p><br />
1. Chop red onion into small rings</p>

<p>2. Heat a blob of olive oil in a saucepan and sauté the onions<br />
 <br />
3. When onions are translucent (but not browned), add the cider and the stock cube</p>

<p>4. Simmer on a medium heat for roughly 20-30mins. At around the 15-20min mark the cider should start to reduce and the alcohol should have evaporated. This sometimes takes slightly longer, so taste the mixture periodically. When the alcohol has evaporated, add the salt/sugar/mixed herbs depending on your taste (it's trickier to gauge the overall flavour before the alcohol has gone)</p>

<p>5. Continue to simmer until the soup has reduced to a nice, thicker consistency</p>

<p>6. Serve in a back garden with black pepper and interesting bread. Note pinkish colouration from the onions.</p>

<p><br />
The means are slightly crooked, but the end results are amazing.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/eddie_nuttall_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/eddie_nuttall_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 09:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Zahra Mani</title>
         <excerpt>Summer Soup / Pistou</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Pistou is French for "Pesto" - this soup is a celebration of home-grown<br />
summer vegetables and olive oil...</p>

<p>Soak about 300 g of dried beans (according to taste) in cold water over<br />
night. (You could use tinned beans if you really must).</p>

<p>The next day, chop up 3 or 4 small-ish, freshly picked courgettes, 3 or 4 <br />
waxy new potatoes, fresh broad beans (all to about half-inch cubes or slices),<br />
and a de-seeded tomato.</p>

<p>Heat a dash of olive oil in a large pot, add all the above (having drained<br />
the dried beans), along with a big sprig of fresh basil, and stir gently<br />
before covering with cold water. Let it come to the boil, then simmer until <br />
the potatoes and beans are cooked - the courgettes shouldn't be too soft.</p>

<p>While the soup is cooking, use a blender to purify as much fresh basil as<br />
you can find with 2 cloves of garlic and the de-seeded flesh of 2 oxheart<br />
(cuore di bue) tomatoes, a generous pinch of sea-salt and a really generous<br />
glug of best extra-vergin olive oil. This is the pistou.</p>

<p>Salt the soup. Then, to serve, pour the pistou into the soup at the table, <br />
and eat with toasted bread with olive oil. Accompanied by a nice crispy <br />
young white wine.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/zahra_mani_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/zahra_mani_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 09:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Christian Fennesz</title>
         <excerpt>Chicken Soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Free Range corn fed chicken breast and legs<br />
Parsley root and leaves<br />
Leek<br />
Red and yellow carrots<br />
Celery<br />
Fennel<br />
A couple of small tomatoes<br />
One large red onion<br />
Salt and pepper</p>

<p>Chop onion in half and place in a large saucepan (like a woman's breasts).<br />
Heat on stove until brown.</p>

<p>Halve the other vegetables and add to the pan.</p>

<p>Throw in the parsley.</p>

<p>Add 2 litres of water to the pan.</p>

<p>Add the chicken.</p>

<p>Gently cook for 3 hours.</p>

<p>Optional: add noodles/dice vegetables.<br />
As you serve, chop ingredients into smaller pieces and add liquid and noodles if required.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/christian_fennesz_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/christian_fennesz_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 09:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Marjolein Kuijsten</title>
         <excerpt>Leftovers Soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>[From dinner eaten on April 1st 2011...]</p>

<p>In a saucepan, bung together:</p>

<p>leftover rice<br />
sajoer (mixed veg & spices and coconut milk)</p>

<p>add water and/or more coconut milk and part of a tablet of mushroom bouillon </p>

<p>heat well and devour</p>

<p>Sampled and enjoyed on April 3rd 2011</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/marjolein_kuijsten.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/marjolein_kuijsten.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 16:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Mike Harding</title>
         <excerpt>Courgette Soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>5 courgette plants are getting ready to deliver their crop in the Touch garden... there will be far too many to eat daily, so I had a look at freezing them, but apparently they go a bit squishy when defrosted. So I investigated a courgette soup recipe... either this or lucky neighbours!</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>

<p>2 lbs (900 g) courgettes<br />
½ lb (225 g) potatoes<br />
4 cloves garlic<br />
1 onion<br />
1½  pints (900 ml) water or white vegetable stock<br />
Salt and Pepper (best is Madagascan pepper - thanks, Philip!)<br />
1 tablespoon chopped basil<br />
1 tablespoon chopped oregano<br />
1 tablesepoon chopped chives<br />
2 tablespoons olive oil<br />
2 oz (56 g) grated parmesan cheese<br />
2 tablespoons cream</p>

<p>Method:</p>

<p>Wash the courgettes and chop into chunks. Peel and cut the potatoes into small cubes.<br />
Peel and slice the onion. Crush the garlic.<br />
Heat the olive oil in a large pan and add the onion and garlic. Lightly fry for about 5 minutes to soften.<br />
Add the potatoes to the pan, cover with half of the stock or water, bring to the boil and then reduce to a simmer for about 15 minutes until half-cooked..<br />
Add the courgette chunks, salt and pepper to taste, chopped oregano and basil and the rest of the stock or water, bring to the boil and then reduce to a simmer for 10 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the potatoes are fully cooked.<br />
Either rub through a sieve or put through a blender to make a smooth pureee.<br />
Return to a clean pan, re-heat and add the cream, grated parmesan and chopped chives without boiling.</p>

<p>Serve immediately with a sprinkling of cheese on the top of the bowls.</p>

<p>Serves 4.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/mike_harding_1.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/mike_harding_1.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Sohrab</title>
         <excerpt>Yoghourt Borrani</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>spinach 500grams<br />
plain yoghurt   1 pack<br />
garlic  1-2 slices<br />
spring onion 1 branch (optional)</p>

<p><br />
This is a very easy quick and yummy to make side dish. its best for summer night dinners!</p>

<p>Wash the spinach and put it in a pot, add some salt and let it cook by itself without adding oil or water. Spinach is a juicy vegetable and we cook it until it lost its water! then put it in a bowl and let it go cold while chopping your garlic.</p>

<p>Add the yoghurt, chopped garlic, and some black pepper to the spinach and mix it well, put it in the fridge for half an hour and then bring it on the table!  you can make decorate it with some rose also (also dried rose)</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/sohrab.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/sohrab.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 09:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Parker</title>
         <excerpt>Onion Soup</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>30g or 1oz of butter<br />
2 tablespoons of sunflower oil<br />
675g or 1½ lbs of onions, halved, and thinly sliced<br />
2 cloves of garlic crushed<br />
½ teaspoon of caster sugar<br />
1 litre or 1¾  pints of vegetable stock (I always use <a href="http://www.marigold-health-foods.com.au/home_page.htm">marigold stock powder</a>)<br />
2 teaspoons of yeast extract or marmite<br />
290ml or ½ pint of dry white wine</p>

<p>Heat the butter and oil in a large heavy saucepan. Add the onions, garlic and sugar and cook over a medium heat for 30 minutes, or even longer, stirring from time to time until the onions are soft and richly caramelized.  </p>

<p>Add the stock, yeast extract and wine and bring to the boil.  Lower the heat, cover and leave to simmer for a further 30 minutes.</p>

<p>The onions never go totally brown, but you want them really really soft and gooey and sticky.  The tiny amount of sugar helps them go a bit darker.  </p>

<p>The yeast extract makes the soup go much more brown, after cooking for 30 minutes.  But never dark brown.  </p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/parker.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/parker.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Vegetarian &amp; Vegan</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 13:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Michael Esposito</title>
         <excerpt>Mormon Funeral Potatoes</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>There are many versions of Funeral Potatoes. Some recipes call for putting cheese (about 1 cup of Cheddar, American or whatever you like) in the potato mixture and using buttered bread crumbs for the topping.</p>

<p>1 1/2 lbs frozen hash brown potatoes, preferrably southern-style diced ones<br />
1 (10 3/4 oz) can condensed cream of celery soup (or cream soup of your choice)<br />
1 (10 3/4 oz) can condensed cream of potato soup<br />
3/4 cup milk<br />
1 pint sour cream<br />
Grated parmesan cheese and butter for topping</p>

<p>Heat over to 350 degrees F.</p>

<p>Mix all the ingredients except cheese and butter, and pour into a shallow baking dish. Top generously with cheese and dot with bits of butter. Bake for 45 to 60 minutes or until bubbly and cheese is lightly browned.</p>

<p>Makes 6 to 8 servings.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/michael_esposito.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/michael_esposito.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Pascal Wyse</title>
         <excerpt>Fried White-truffle Eggs</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>First you need to hunt down an Italian white truffle, tuber magnatum. For this you will need a dog that has been trained to get very excited at the smell of one. Pigs get excited, but they are harder to wrestle away from the treasure when they find it.  You also need to know where to look, which is still a bit of a mystery to be honest (Plutarch decided they occur where lightning meets thunder, if that helps). To save time, buy one in a shop, at mind-boggling expense.</p>

<p>Really you should eat it as soon as possible, but if you can bear the wait, place the truffle in an airtight container in the fridge, accompanied by a few eggs and some unsalted butter out of its wrapping. Leave overnight and they will absorb a little of the smell.</p>

<p>Before you cook, bring the eggs to come back to room temperature out of the fridge. Melt some of the butter until it starts to foam a little, then add the eggs. You can fry them, but to preserve every bit of the aphrodisiac perfume, cover the pan and use a low heat. Serve on a hot plate, add salt and grate (using a truffle slicer or a potato peeler) enough tuber magnatum over them to disguise the fact that they are eggs.</p>

<p>Stick your head right over the plate, take a very deep breath through your nose, then eat.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/pascal_wyse.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/pascal_wyse.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Stephen O&apos;Malley</title>
         <excerpt>AXA9LING&apos;s Edemame Humous of the Gods</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>1 bag frozen shelled edamame<br />
2 tbs peanut oil<br />
1/4 cup canola oil<br />
1/4 cup seasoned rice vinegar<br />
1/4 cup rice vinegar<br />
salt & pepper<br />
3 scallions<br />
chunk of fresh ginger, chopped</p>

<p>Boil the edamame for 4-5 minutes, then drain.<br />
Put the scallions and ginger in a food processor and mince very fine.<br />
Add the rest of the ingredients and process until smooth.<br />
Add more rice vinegar, salt and pepper to taste<br />
The original recipe has much more oil but I don't think you need it.<br />
If the hummus is too thick without the oil, add a little water.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/stephen_omalley.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/stephen_omalley.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
            <item>
         <title>Phill Niblock</title>
         <excerpt>Bean Soup Ei Style</excerpt>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Two boxes (or bags) of beans, preferably different, soaked overnight and drained</p>

<p>Garlic, chopped or crushed, browned in olive oil, one head / large several onions, chopped fine and browned as well<br />
Sweet peppers, various colors, chopped and browned<br />
Mushrooms, chopped and browned</p>

<p>Carrots, six to ten, chopped to bite size pieces<br />
Other vegetables - broccoli, zuchini, tomatos, etc</p>

<p>Make as vegetarian. in a separate pot, fry chopped bacon. add soup to this pot to make a meat version.</p>

<p>Cook beans and browned vegetables for several hours (say 6), add other vegetables one to two hours before first serving.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/phill_niblock.html</link>
         <guid>http://touch33.net/recipebook/soups_starters/phill_niblock.html</guid>
                  <category domain="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category">Soups &amp; Starters</category>
        
        
         <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 15:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
      
   </channel>
</rss>